<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 16:41:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Google Play 將支持請他人為應用購買付款</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/1716644737_google-play-store-ask-someone-else-payment-button_story.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Play 應用商店將允許其他人為你的應用購買付款。&lt;/strong&gt;為此該商店新增了一個 「要求其他人為此項目付款」 按鈕。在 Play 商店購買應用或遊戲時，用户可邀請朋友或家人為想要的應用付費，付款人需要在 24 小時內對生成的支付鏈接付款，之後鏈接將過期。點擊該按鈕的用户會收到警告，因為付款人需要知道 TA 的電子郵件地址，以及想購買的商品。該按鈕率先在印度推出，預計很快會出現在其他地區。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Google Play app store now allows others to make purchases and payments for your apps. To enable this feature, the store has introduced a 「Request payment from others」 button. When purchasing apps or games on the Play Store, users can invite friends or family to pay for the desired apps. This button was initially launched in India and is expected to roll out to other regions soon. Users who click on this button will receive a warning, as the payer will need to know their email address and the item they wish to purchase. The payer must make the payment within 24 hours of receiving the generated payment link, as the link will expire thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143122.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143122.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 11:10:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>阿里巴巴正對淘寶頻繁改版</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐持續跟蹤發現，&lt;strong&gt;阿里巴巴正在對淘寶客户端進行頻繁的改版嘗試。&lt;/strong&gt;改版似乎正朝着更加緊湊、清爽、簡單的方向進行，這體現在淘寶 App 首頁（推薦）、個人中心、商品搜索頁等多處。在我們的多台測試設備上，同一版本的淘寶客户端的界面呈現各不相同，淘寶正針對不同用户測試不同的改版方案。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;本月初，淘寶還稱&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142943.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;全面重啓對淘寶 PC 站的優化工作，以及重開淘寶論壇&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alibaba is actively making frequent attempts to revamp the Taobao mobile app. The redesign appears to be moving towards a more compact, refreshing, and simplified direction, which is evident in various sections, including the Taobao app homepage (recommendations), personal center, and product search pages. On our multiple testing devices, the interface of the Taobao app varies among the same version, as Alibaba is testing different redesign strategies for different users.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143120.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143120.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 11:02:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>iOS 18 可用 AI 生成表情符號</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;科技記者 Mark Gurman 透露，&lt;strong&gt;iOS 18 將提供一個 AI 工具，允許用户生成自定義表情符號。&lt;/strong&gt;該工具不是獨立的 App，它根據用户在文本框中輸入的內容直接生成表情符號。此外，語音助手 Siri 將藉助 AI 技術讓發音更加自然，並且將有可能自定義應用圖標的顏色。用户可將這些圖標放置在自定義的位置，而不侷限於 iOS 應用網格的固定順序。該公司還希望將 Siri 用到的 AI 技術應用於 Xcode，以為開發人員提供支持。蘋果希望在設備本地完成大部分 AI 任務的處理，某些密集任務可能會通過雲端處理。這些雲計算使用的是 M2 Ultra 芯片，能夠以隱私友好的方式處理數據。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tech journalist Mark Gurman revealed that iOS 18 will feature an AI tool that allows users to generate custom emojis. This functionality will not be a separate app; instead, it will generate emojis based on the user’s input in a text box. Additionally, the voice assistant Siri will sound more natural thanks to AI technology, and there will be the possibility to customize the color of app icons. Users will also have the ability to place these icons in custom locations rather than being restricted to a fixed order in the iOS app grid. The company also intends to apply the AI technology used by Siri to Xcode, providing support for developers. Apple aims to process the majority of AI tasks on the device itself, while some intensive tasks may be processed in the cloud. These cloud computations will utilize the M2 Ultra chip, which can handle data in a privacy-friendly manner.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143112.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143112.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:41:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>英國 2026 年起允許自動駕駛汽車上路</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;近日，英國通過了法案 Automated Vehicles Bill，根據該法案，&lt;strong&gt;從 2026 年開始，完全自動駕駛的車輛將被允許在英國的公共道路上行駛&lt;/strong&gt;。車輛中仍需要有一名駕駛員，但在自動駕駛模式下，駕駛員不再對車輛的行為負責。前提是這些車輛 「在自動駕駛模式下與謹慎和能幹的人類駕駛員一樣安全或更安全」。為此，政府計劃建立一個 「批准制度」，並設立一個 「獨立的事故調查職能」。當局稱企業必須履行持續的義務，以確保其車輛的安全性。英國政府認為，自動駕駛車輛可提高交通的可訪問性，因為不會開車的人也可以上路了。英國交通部長馬克·哈珀（Mark Harper）將該法案的批准是 「對安全和經濟的巨大推動」。預計到 2035 年，自動駕駛汽車行業的價值將達到 420 億英鎊（480 億歐元），並創造 38,000 個就業機會。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recently, the United Kingdom passed the Automated Vehicles Bill, which allows fully autonomous vehicles to operate on public roads starting from 2026. While a driver is still required to be present in the vehicle, they are no longer responsible for the vehicle’s behavior in autonomous mode. The condition is that these vehicles must be 「as safe as or safer than cautious and competent human drivers」 in autonomous mode. The government plans to establish an approval system and create an independent incident investigation function. Companies are required to fulfill ongoing obligations to ensure the safety of their vehicles. The UK government believes that autonomous vehicles can improve transportation accessibility, as even individuals who cannot drive can now take to the roads. The approval of the bill by the UK Transport Minister, Mark Harper, is seen as a significant boost for both safety and the economy. It is estimated that by 2035, the autonomous vehicle industry could be worth £42 billion (€48 billion) and create 38,000 jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143106.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143106.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>