<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 16:35:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>截屏工具 FastStone Capture 支持「固定到屏幕」和「文本提取」</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;备受欢迎的 Windows 截屏工具 FastStone Capture 于 2024 年 5 月底发布了最新版本，即 FastStone Capture 10.5（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faststone.org/FSCaptureDownload.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;官网下载页&lt;/a&gt;）。&lt;/strong&gt;新版本新增了 「固定到屏幕」 和 「捕获文本」 功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;顾名思义，「固定到屏幕」（界面上译为 「屏幕贴图」）允许用户将截屏固定在电脑屏幕上，以便在不同的应用程序之间切换。「捕获文本」 则允许用户直接从屏幕截图中提取文本。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;添加了 「固定到屏幕」。此功能允许您在其他窗口（如便笺）上固定和注释屏幕截图。优势包括：
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;参考便利性：如果您正在处理一项需要您经常参考屏幕截图的任务，将其固定在屏幕上可以使您免于不断切换窗口或应用程序。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;高效比较：当您需要比较应用程序之间的数据时，固定屏幕截图可以更轻松地同时查看两组数据，而无需第二台显示器。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;视觉提醒：固定捕获可以作为需要完成的任务或需要注意的信息的视觉提醒，从而减少忘记重要细节的机会。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;添加了 「捕获文本」。此功能可以提取文本并使其可立即编辑，从而节省时间和精力，而不是从屏幕截图中手动键入文本。它需要 Windows 10/11。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;进行了其他改进和错误修复&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The popular Windows screenshot tool, FastStone Capture, released its latest version, FastStone Capture 10.5, at the end of May 2024. The new version introduces the 「Pin to Screen」 and 「Capture Text」 features.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, the 「Pin to Screen」 (translated as 「Screen Magnifier」 in the interface) allows users to pin the screenshot to their computer screen for easy switching between different applications. The 「Capture Text」 feature enables users to extract text directly from the screen captures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Screen Recorder&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplified&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Start Recording&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;window. Switch between simplified mode and detailed mode with just a single click&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enable&lt;/strong&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;disable&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;devices&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;like Microphone, Speaker, and Webcam directly&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;within&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Start Recording&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Enhanced&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Eraser&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Draw tool:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show a&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;circular cursor&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;to indicate the area to be erased.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Right click mouse to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;pick a screen color&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Scroll mouse wheel to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;adjust eraser size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Save dialog&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Scan&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;tool with improved functionality and user interface.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Added 「&lt;strong&gt;Save All (same name)&lt;/strong&gt;」 option (Ctrl+Alt+S) to the File menu in FastStone Editor, allowing you to save multiple images with the same name and a sequential number&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Many other small enhancements and bug fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143235.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143235.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 16:31:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>图形图像</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>电子书网站 Z-Library 主要域名再被查封</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;电子书网站 Z-Library 称其一个主要域名被当局查封，该网站因此遭遇技术问题，目前仍在努力恢复。&lt;/strong&gt;该网站没有提及查封域名的当局名称。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;亲爱的 Z-Librarians，&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;由于我们的一个主要域名被没收，我们正在经历一些技术问题。我们的团队正在努力恢复功能。&lt;br&gt;捐款的入账可能会有延迟，但请不要担心 – 系统将自动将其计入，并尽快升级您的账户为高级会员状态。&lt;br&gt;请注意，可能会有人冒充我们的图书馆进行欺诈活动，同时请记住，我们的网站不提供终身高级会员资格。该网站仍然可以通过以下链接访问：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;singlelogin.re&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;singlelogin.rs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;我们目前正在努力恢复我们的支持团队，以便他们能够回复您的所有消息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The e-book website Z-Library has reported that one of its main domains has been seized by authorities, resulting in technical issues for the website. Efforts are currently underway to restore its functionality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Z-Librarians,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Since one of our main domains was seized, we are experiencing some technical issues. Our team is already working to restore functionality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There may be delays in crediting donations, but don’t worry – the system will automatically credit them and upgrade your accounts to premium status as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Please pay attention to possible fraudulent activities on behalf of our library, and remember that our site does not offer lifetime premium status. The website is still available via the links below:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;singlelogin.re&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;singlelogin.rs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on getting our support team back up, so they can reply to all your messages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your understanding and patience ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143223.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143223.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:55:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[技巧] 关闭 Firefox 安卓版的遥测功能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;要关闭 Firefox 安卓版的遥测功能非常简单，只需进入浏览器的设置界面，点击数据收集，将以下三项开关关即可。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;使用率和技术数据&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;营销数据&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;研究&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;关闭 Firefox 安卓版的遥测功能可&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/143209.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;提升浏览器的性能&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143216.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143216.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:43:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>遥测功能降低了 Firefox 安卓版的性能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;遥测功能似乎影响了 &lt;strong&gt;Firefox 安卓版&lt;/strong&gt;的性能，Mozilla 已对此展开调查。&lt;/strong&gt;根据初步报告，遥测会增加额外的 CPU 时间。其中一项测试显示，在加载 CNN 网站时，遥测使 Firefox 安卓版增加了额外的 16.5 秒 CPU 时间。此外，浏览器的启动也受到遥测的影响——与关闭遥测相比，启动浏览器会增加 40% 的 CPU 时间。Mozilla 表示，问题的根源在于 Android 上的遥测更新没有进行分组，因此每次更新都会单独添加到数据库中。此外，每次更新都会将整个数据库写入磁盘。由于遥测数据被广泛收集，因此会执行大量的写操作。这会对浏览器的启动、网页加载和媒体播放等方面产生影响。&lt;strong&gt;在 Mozilla 改进之前，Android 用户可以选择在浏览器中关闭遥测以获得更好的性能。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/143216.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;关闭方法&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The telemetry feature of Firefox for Android appears to be impacting the performance of the browser, and Mozilla has initiated an investigation into this matter. According to preliminary reports, telemetry adds additional CPU time. One test showed that while loading the CNN website, telemetry added an extra 16.5 seconds of CPU time to Firefox for Android. Additionally, the startup of the browser is also affected by telemetry, with a 40% increase in CPU time compared to when telemetry is disabled. Mozilla states that the root cause of the issue lies in the fact that telemetry updates on Android are not grouped, leading to individual additions to the database with each update. Furthermore, every update requires writing the entire database to disk. Since telemetry data is collected extensively, it results in a significant number of write operations. This has an impact on browser startup, webpage loading, and media playback. Until Mozilla addresses the issue, Android users can choose to disable telemetry in the browser for improved performance.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143209.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143209.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:43:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Netflix 宣布将推出《我的世界》动画剧集</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netflix 宣布将推出一部围绕视频游戏 Minecraft（我的世界）的动画剧集。&lt;/strong&gt;这家流媒体平台提到了一个 「带有全新角色的原创故事」。发布日期尚未公布。已释出的预告片展示了下界与爬行者的地下世界。这部剧集由加拿大工作室 WildBrain Studios 制作，该机构曾为 Netflix 制作过几部儿童剧集和《Sonic Prime》。此外，还有一部 Minecraft 主题电影正在开发中，杰克·布莱克（Jack Black）可能会扮演主角。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Netflix has announced the upcoming release of an animated series based on the video game Minecraft. The streaming platform mentions an 「original story with new characters.」 The release date has not been revealed yet. The teaser trailer showcases the Nether, an underground world, and a Creeper. There is no indication of the plot at this time. The animated series is being produced by Canadian studio WildBrain Studios, known for creating several children’s series and 「Sonic Prime」 for Netflix. Additionally, there is an ongoing development of a Minecraft-themed film, with actor Jack Black rumored to have a leading role.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143204.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143204.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:22:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>