<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 07:52:11 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>X（Twitter）对成人内容放宽政策</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-wpcom-alert&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info block-alert&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文是客观报道，本站及作者对报道对象不持立场。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;X（Twitter）似乎决定针对成人内容放宽政策。&lt;/strong&gt;因为该平台最近发布了一个新的成人内容政策页面。页面显示，X 用户现在可以发布带有 「成人裸体或性行为」 的内容，但将有一些限制。该平台认为此类内容 「可以成为一种合法的艺术表达形式」。与此同时，X 将针对这些内容覆盖内容警告信息，未登记生日的未成年用户将无法通过内容警告以浏览这些内容。X 账户头像或横幅中也禁止放置成人内容。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;这并不意味着 X 允许任何成人内容，因为该平台仍然禁止任何可以标记为 「剥削、未经同意、物化、性化或伤害未成年人以及淫秽行为」 的成人内容。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;这次同时发布的还有一个新的暴力内容政策页面。X 官方表示，这两个新政策页面都取代了其以前的敏感媒体和暴力言论政策。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;X (Twitter) appears to have decided to relax its policies against adult content. The platform recently published a new adult content policy page , which reveals that X users are now able to post content that features 「nudity or sexual activity」 so long as certain restrictions are met. The platform believes that such content 「can be a legitimate form of artistic expression.」 X will, however, cover such content with an interstitial warning, and underage users who have not registered their birthday will not be able to proceed past the warning to view the content. Adult content will also be prohibited in X account profile pictures and banners. This doesn’t mean that X will allow any adult content, as the platform will still ban any adult content that could be flagged as 「exploitative, non-consensual, objectifying, dehumanizing or grooming minors, as well as pornography.」 Also rolling out today is a new support page for its violent content policy . 「These new policy pages replace our previous Sensitive Media and Violent Speech policies,」 an X spokesperson says.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143270.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143270.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[清单] 2024 年 5 月 Telegram 更新要点</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，Telegram（电报）于上个月底发布了 2024 年 5 月份的版本更新。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;我们从冗长的更新日志中梳理了更新要点。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.org/blog/message-effects-and-more#message-effects&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;私聊消息动画效果&lt;/strong&gt;。现在，Telegram 私聊消息可以动画效果发送，对方打开聊天时会播放这些效果。Telegram 免费提供 6 种效果，Telegram Premium 用户可解锁数百种效果。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;媒体上方的字幕。&lt;/strong&gt;标题现在可移动到媒体上方。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;手机号码的快速操作&lt;/strong&gt;。在聊天中点击手机号码会打开新菜单，可快速发送消息、通话或将号码添加为联系人。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;主题标签搜索&lt;/strong&gt;。现在，在任何聊天中点击主题标签可显示来自公共频道的搜索结果。例如快速找到频 &lt;code&gt;#news&lt;/code&gt;&amp;nbsp; 或 &lt;code&gt;#travel&lt;/code&gt;&amp;nbsp; 视频。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;可折叠的引用&lt;/strong&gt;。现在可将文本片段隐藏在折叠的引用块中，消息更紧凑。只需添加引用格式，并在输入框中点击折叠按钮。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS 上的彩色通话&lt;/strong&gt;。现在，Telegram 原生 macOS 应用程序用户可使用彩色通话界面，包括动态背景和时尚动画。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143243.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143243.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 15:00:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>特朗普入驻 TikTok</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;共和党总统候选人特朗普 (Donald Trump) 入驻了短视频平台 TikTok。&lt;/strong&gt;该账号在周日早间粉丝超过 80 万。上周六晚，特朗普发布一段了 13 秒的短视频，是他在新泽西州纽瓦克的终极格斗冠军赛（简称 UFC) 活动的视频。视频中，特朗普在赛场内向粉丝致意。特朗普希望通过加入 TikTok 来拉拢年轻选民。而就在四年前，特朗普在总统任上曾试图下令封禁 TikTok，但因法律问题未能如愿。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has joined the short video platform TikTok. The account garnered over 800,000 followers on Sunday morning. Last Saturday night, Trump released a 13-second video showcasing his presence at the Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) event in Newark, New Jersey. In the video, Trump greeted his fans inside the arena. By joining TikTok, Trump aims to attract young voters. Interestingly, just four years ago, during his presidency, Trump attempted to ban TikTok, but his efforts were hindered by legal challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143241.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143241.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:54:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Cloud 推出条件宽松的 90 天试用计划</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，谷歌云（Google Cloud）为了推广 Vertex AI，日前推出了免费试用计划，用户可从 Google Cloud 获得 150 美元的赠送金，可在 3 个月内体验 Vertex AI 及 Google Cloud，包括在 Google Cloud 上创建虚拟机。&lt;strong&gt;我们测试发现，申请这项体验计划无需验证信用卡或银行卡，甚至点击 「免费试用 Vertex AI」 体验按钮，即可直接通过申请。&lt;/strong&gt;后续还可激活账号（需验卡）可再获得 150 美元赠金。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;如果读者在申请时弹出验证信用卡或银行卡界面，说明 IP 不满足条件，可考虑更换一个新的 IP 再次申请。&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai?hl=zh_cn&quot;&gt;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai?hl=zh_cn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud has recently launched a free trial program to promote Vertex AI. Users can receive a $150 credit from Google Cloud to experience Vertex AI and Google Cloud services for three months, including creating virtual machines on Google Cloud. Our testing has found that applying for this trial program does not require credit card or bank card verification. Users can simply click the 「Free Trial Vertex AI」 button to apply directly. Afterward, activating the account (requires card verification) will provide an additional $150 credit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If readers encounter a credit card or bank card verification prompt during the application process, it indicates that the IP does not meet the requirements. In this case, consider changing to a new IP and reapplying.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143238.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143238.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:12:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>截屏工具 FastStone Capture 支持「固定到屏幕」和「文本提取」</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;备受欢迎的 Windows 截屏工具 FastStone Capture 于 2024 年 5 月底发布了最新版本，即 FastStone Capture 10.5（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faststone.org/FSCaptureDownload.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;官网下载页&lt;/a&gt;）。&lt;/strong&gt;新版本新增了 「固定到屏幕」 和 「捕获文本」 功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;顾名思义，「固定到屏幕」（界面上译为 「屏幕贴图」）允许用户将截屏固定在电脑屏幕上，以便在不同的应用程序之间切换。「捕获文本」 则允许用户直接从屏幕截图中提取文本。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;添加了 「固定到屏幕」。此功能允许您在其他窗口（如便笺）上固定和注释屏幕截图。优势包括：
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;参考便利性：如果您正在处理一项需要您经常参考屏幕截图的任务，将其固定在屏幕上可以使您免于不断切换窗口或应用程序。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;高效比较：当您需要比较应用程序之间的数据时，固定屏幕截图可以更轻松地同时查看两组数据，而无需第二台显示器。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;视觉提醒：固定捕获可以作为需要完成的任务或需要注意的信息的视觉提醒，从而减少忘记重要细节的机会。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;添加了 「捕获文本」。此功能可以提取文本并使其可立即编辑，从而节省时间和精力，而不是从屏幕截图中手动键入文本。它需要 Windows 10/11。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;进行了其他改进和错误修复&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The popular Windows screenshot tool, FastStone Capture, released its latest version, FastStone Capture 10.5, at the end of May 2024. The new version introduces the 「Pin to Screen」 and 「Capture Text」 features.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, the 「Pin to Screen」 (translated as 「Screen Magnifier」 in the interface) allows users to pin the screenshot to their computer screen for easy switching between different applications. The 「Capture Text」 feature enables users to extract text directly from the screen captures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Screen Recorder&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplified&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Start Recording&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;window. Switch between simplified mode and detailed mode with just a single click&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enable&lt;/strong&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;disable&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;devices&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;like Microphone, Speaker, and Webcam directly&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;within&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Start Recording&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Enhanced&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Eraser&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Draw tool:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show a&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;circular cursor&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;to indicate the area to be erased.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Right click mouse to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;pick a screen color&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Scroll mouse wheel to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;adjust eraser size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Save dialog&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Scan&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;tool with improved functionality and user interface.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Added 「&lt;strong&gt;Save All (same name)&lt;/strong&gt;」 option (Ctrl+Alt+S) to the File menu in FastStone Editor, allowing you to save multiple images with the same name and a sequential number&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Many other small enhancements and bug fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143235.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143235.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 16:31:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>图形图像</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>