<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 14:59:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Netflix 宣布将推出《我的世界》动画剧集</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netflix 宣布将推出一部围绕视频游戏 Minecraft（我的世界）的动画剧集。&lt;/strong&gt;这家流媒体平台提到了一个 「带有全新角色的原创故事」。发布日期尚未公布。已释出的预告片展示了下界与爬行者的地下世界。这部剧集由加拿大工作室 WildBrain Studios 制作，该机构曾为 Netflix 制作过几部儿童剧集和《Sonic Prime》。此外，还有一部 Minecraft 主题电影正在开发中，杰克·布莱克（Jack Black）可能会扮演主角。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Netflix has announced the upcoming release of an animated series based on the video game Minecraft. The streaming platform mentions an 「original story with new characters.」 The release date has not been revealed yet. The teaser trailer showcases the Nether, an underground world, and a Creeper. There is no indication of the plot at this time. The animated series is being produced by Canadian studio WildBrain Studios, known for creating several children’s series and 「Sonic Prime」 for Netflix. Additionally, there is an ongoing development of a Minecraft-themed film, with actor Jack Black rumored to have a leading role.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143204.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143204.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:22:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Via 浏览器更新，新增复制标签页功能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;以轻快简洁见长的 Via 浏览器最近发布了最新版本 Via Browser 5.6.1。&lt;/strong&gt;该版本推出了多项新功能及改进。其中带来了 「标签页菜单复制标签」 功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Play 商店：&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mark.via.gp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mark.via.gp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– 标签页菜单新增复制标签选项&lt;br&gt;– 主菜单新增其它应用打开选项&lt;br&gt;– 优化用户脚本的兼容性&lt;br&gt;– 脚本支持 data 协议的依赖资源&lt;br&gt;– 修复阅读模式下打印页面异常的错误&lt;br&gt;– 修复过滤规则可能被错误清空的问题&lt;br&gt;– 其它错误修复&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143187.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143187.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 11:58:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>苹果 Apple TV+正开发安卓版本</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;苹果发布的招聘信息显示，该公司计划将 Apple TV+服务引入 Android 手机和平板电脑。&lt;/strong&gt;苹果正在寻找一位 Android 工程师，负责开发一款 「被数百万用户用来观看电视和体育赛事」 的应用程序。Apple TV+已在搭载 Google TV 的 Chromecast 和运行 Android 系统的智能电视上可用，但尚未支持 Android 手机和平板电脑。目前只有少数几款苹果应用程序为 Android 推出了适用版本，例如 Apple Music、Beats 和 Move to iOS 等。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bloomberg: Apple is planning to bring its Apple TV+ service to Android phones and tablets. According to a job listing released by the company, Apple is seeking an Android engineer to develop an application 「used by millions to watch TV and sports.」 While Apple TV+ is already available on devices such as Google TV-powered Chromecast and Android-based smart TVs, it currently lacks support for Android phones and tablets. Apple’s decision to develop apps for other operating systems is uncommon, with only a few Apple applications, such as Apple Music, Beats, and Move to iOS, having versions available for Android. The timing of when the TV+ app will become available for Android phones remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143166.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143166.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 08:28:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Windows Copilot 已被集成到微软桌面</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;微软的人工智能助理应用 Windows Copilot 已被集成到微软桌面（Microsoft Launcher）的最新 Beta 版中。&lt;/strong&gt;Google Play（&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.launcher&amp;amp;hl=en-US&amp;amp;ah=8cxnoy1ug9VptVgQxqniZsdMMbM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;链接&lt;/a&gt;）已经上架了这个版本。与此同时旧版的 Bing Chat 图标已被 Copilot 取代。因为微软已经放弃了 Bing Chat 品牌。需要指出，微软桌面中的 Copilot 功能有限，不包含 Copilot Pro 的假期计划、烹饪助手、健身教练和笔记本等功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s artificial intelligence assistant application, Windows Copilot, has been integrated into the latest beta version of Microsoft Launcher. This version is now available on Google Play (link). Additionally, the old Bing Chat icon has been replaced by Copilot, as Microsoft has discontinued the Bing Chat brand. It should be noted that the Copilot functionality in Microsoft Launcher is limited and does not include features such as Copilot Pro’s vacation planner, cooking assistant, fitness coach, and notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143128.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143128.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 08:31:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>油管迎来「听歌识曲」功能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;谷歌为 YouTube 和 YouTube Music 的安卓版本推出了类似 Shazam 的听歌识曲功能。&lt;/strong&gt;用户可通过哼唱、吹口哨或播放录音来让 YouTube 识别歌曲。在两款应用的搜索栏右侧的麦克风图标旁可以访问该功能。暂不清楚谷歌何时会将该功能向 iOS 用户推出。2020 年，谷歌向 Google Assistent 引入了类似的功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google has introduced a Shazam-like song recognition feature for the Android versions of YouTube and YouTube Music. Users can identify songs on YouTube by humming, whistling, or playing a recording. The feature is accessible through the microphone icon next to the search bar in both applications. It is currently unknown when Google will release this feature for iOS users. In 2020, Google introduced a similar feature to Google Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143126.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143126.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 08:21:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓应用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>