<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 10:40:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Android 项目主要领导者 Dave Burke 在谷歌内部调岗</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;谷歌工程副总裁戴夫·伯克（Dave Burke）将在 Google 内部调岗。&lt;/strong&gt;作为 Android 项目的主要领导者之一，Dave Burke 以在 I/O 开发者大会上的 Google 主题演讲而闻名，他在演讲中讨论新的 Android 功能。调岗后，他将转向 AI 和生物技术领域。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dave Burke 的调岗是 Google 内部重组的一部分——Google 正在将其 Android 和 ChromeOS 等操作系统开发部门与 Pixel 手机和 Chromebook 等硬件开发部门合并。该公司将把 Android 内核和框架插入 ChromeOS。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google engineering VP Dave Burke is shifting roles within Google. One of the lead executives for the Android project, Burke was known for leading Google’s keynote at the I/O developer conference, where he’d discuss new Android features. In his new role, he’ll be moving to work on AI and biotech. Burke’s shift is part of a reorganization within Google that will see the company combine its operating system development efforts across Android and ChromeOS with its hardware development for devices like Pixel phones and Chromebooks. The company will merge the core of Android with ChromeOS.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143464.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143464.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 10:11:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Drive 新功能：邮件提醒查看他人分享的文件</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/2024061309350985.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;Google 云端硬盘已开始发送电子邮件，以提醒客户处理与他们共享但尚未查看的文件。&lt;/strong&gt;谷歌称其为 Drive Digest，只有当客户在 7 天内未登录并且其他用户共享了他们尚未查看的文件时，他们才会收到电子邮件提醒。这是一项 Workspace 功能，尚不清楚是否适用于私人帐户。该功能将在未来几周内发布，谷歌允许在设置中关闭通知。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Drive is starting to send out emails to remind customers about files shared with them that they haven’t gotten around to looking at yet. Google calls it Drive Digest , and you’ll only get the email reminders if you haven’t signed in for seven days and you have files shared with you that you haven’t viewed. This is a Workspace feature, and it’s not clear if it will also be available to personal accounts. The rollout of this feature will happen over the next few weeks, and Google will let you turn off the notifications in your settings .&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143458.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143458.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 09:36:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>你在 X（Twitter）的点赞现在是私密的</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/2024061309240816.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;X 已经开始隐藏用户的 「喜欢」/点赞数据——贴子仍会显示收到了多少赞，但在某位用户的主页无法再看到 TA 点赞的内容。&lt;/strong&gt;贴子作者仍能继续看到谁点赞了自己的帖子。我们实测看到，这项改动已经生效，X 已经弹窗进行提示 「你的点赞现在是私密的」。X（Twitter）表示，个人点赞数据公开经常受到批评，因为用户有时会将该机制用作书签，而不代表他们喜欢或支持某篇帖子。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;由于隐私增强，上述改动可能会进一步提升 X（Twitter）用户点赞的积极性。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;X has begun hiding users’ like/favorite counts — posts will still show how many likes they have received, but there’s no longer any way to see what someone has liked from their profile. The author of a post will still be able to see who liked their post. The change appears to be rolling out now, with X showing a pop-up notification that reads, 「Your likes are now private.」 X (Twitter) said that public like counts were often criticized because people sometimes used the feature as a bookmarking tool rather than a way to indicate that they enjoyed or supported a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143447.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143447.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 09:31:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2024 年 6 月更新修复了 Win11 任务栏卡顿/无响应问题</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，微软表示，&lt;strong&gt;本周二发布的 2024 年 6 月的 Patch Tuesday 更新，已修复了 Windows 11 任务栏偶尔出现卡顿、无响应、消失后重显等问题，以及 Windows 11 21H2 中的 BitLocker 65000 错误。&lt;/strong&gt;BitLocker 65000 错误出现于去年 10 月。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;微软本周二发布了 2024 年 6 月的 Patch Tuesday 更新，适用于 Windows 11（KB5039212 / KB5039213）和 Windows 10（KB5039211 / KB5039217 / KB5039214 / KB5039225）。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft says that this week’s Patch Tuesday updates, released on June 13, 2023, fixes issues with the Windows 11 taskbar occasionally getting stuck or unresponsive, disappearing and reappearing, and the BitLocker 65000 error that started appearing in Windows 11 21H2 in October last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft released the June 2023 Patch Tuesday updates on Tuesday and they include updates for Windows 11 (KB5039212 / KB5039213) and Windows 10 (KB5039211 / KB5039217 / KB5039214 / KB5039225).&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143435.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143435.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 03:34:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Spotify 高保真订阅每月额外收费 5 美元</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;据彭博社，音频流媒体平台 Spotify 的高保真音频订阅计划每月额外收费 5 美元。&lt;/strong&gt;这项订阅计划可能在今年晚些时候发布。除了更高质量的音频外，高保真计划订户将获得更多个性化播放列表，此外客户可以创建带有提示的播放列表，然后 Spotify 会尝试找到正确的歌曲。Spotify 尚未回应上述传闻。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Bloomberg, audio streaming platform Spotify is planning to introduce a high-fidelity audio subscription plan with an additional monthly charge of $5. This subscription plan is expected to be released later this year. In addition to higher quality audio, high-fidelity plan subscribers will have access to more personalized playlists. Furthermore, customers will be able to create playlists with cues, and Spotify will attempt to find the right songs. Spotify has not yet responded to the aforementioned rumors.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143402.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143402.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 02:33:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娱乐</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>