<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Jun 2024 16:36:40 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Windows 虚拟机软件 NanaBox 支持 TPM 2.0</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;Windows 虚拟机软件 NanaBox 最近推出了对 TPM 2.0 的支持。&lt;/strong&gt;NanaBox 是一款年轻的虚拟化软件，发布于 2022 年（&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/M2Team/NanaBox/releases/tag/1.2.797.0&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;GitHub&lt;/a&gt;）。最新版的 NanaBox 1.2 Update 2（1.2.797.0）在更新日志提及了上述改进：「此更新引入了对 Windows Server 2022 或更高版本主机操作系统中的虚拟机的受信任平台模块（TPM）2.0 支持。」&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;其同类软件 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/107817.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;VirtualBox&lt;/a&gt;、&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/113326.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;VMware&lt;/a&gt; 等更早之前即已支持 TPM 2.0。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Windows virtual machine software NanaBox recently introduced support for TPM 2.0. NanaBox is a young virtualization software, released in 2022. The latest version of NanaBox 1.2 Update 2 (1.2.797.0) mentioned the above improvements in the update log: 「This update introduces support for Trusted Platform Module (TPM) 2.0 for virtual machines on Windows Server 2022 or later host operating systems.」&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Similar software such as VirtualBox and VMware have supported TPM 2.0 earlier.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143380.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143380.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 10:08:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>苹果下周发布独立的密码管理器 App</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，彭博社记者马克·古尔曼（Mark Gurman）称，&lt;strong&gt;苹果公司将于 6 月 10 日在 WWDC 上推出自己的密码管理器。它将适用于 iOS 18、iPadOS 18 和 macOS 15。&lt;/strong&gt;该密码管理器将被称为 「Passwords」，可与 iCloud 钥匙串配合使用。它跟踪所有设备上的用户密码，可以在 「设置」 中找到。该应用程序包括登录列表，并提供分类功能（例如帐户、Wi-Fi 网络和密钥），支持自动填充。它还可以在 Vision Pro 头显和 Windows 上运行。&lt;strong&gt;苹果希望借此为用户提供一个清晰的密码应用程序，以与 1Password 和 LastPass 等密码管理器竞争。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Apple will introduce its own password manager at WWDC on June 10, according to Bloomberg’s Mark Gurman. It will be available for iOS 18, iPadOS 18, and macOS 13. The password manager will be called 「Passwords」 and will work with the iCloud Keychain. It will keep track of users’ passwords across their devices and will be accessible in the Settings app. The app will feature a list of logins and will have an organizational structure (like accounts, Wi-Fi networks, and secure notes), complete with autofill support. It will also be available on the rumored mixed-reality headset and on Windows. With this move, Apple looks to provide users with a first-party password application to rival password managers like 1Password and LastPass.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143342.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143342.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 09:01:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>微软宣布重启 Win10 Beta 通道，将发布新功能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;微软正在重新开放 Windows 10 的 Beta 频道，并称将为 Win10 提供 「新功能和更多改进」。&lt;/strong&gt;微软将在未来几周内发布第一个新的 Beta 版本。此举令人意外，因为微软一年前已宣布 Windows 10 不再获得任何新功能。通过 Beta 频道，Windows 10 用户可以继续留在 Windows 10，而不是升级到 Windows 11。不过，Windows 10 的终止时间不会因为 Beta 频道的 「复活」 而改变，它将于 2025 年 10 月 14 日退出历史舞台。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is reopening the Beta Channel for Windows 10, saying it will give the software 「new features and further improvements.」 Microsoft will release its first new Beta build in the coming weeks. The move is a surprise, coming a year after Microsoft said that Windows 10 would no longer receive new features. The Beta Channel gives Windows 10 users a way to keep using Windows 10 instead of upgrading to Windows 11 . However, the end-of-support date for Windows 10 won’t change as a result of the Beta Channel’s resurrection: it’s still scheduled to be retired on October 14, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143315.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143315.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 03:00:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 10</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Firefox 浏览器最新支持「标签页预览」</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;Mozilla 将为 Firefox 浏览器推出标签页预览功能。&lt;/strong&gt;现在 Firefox Nightly 已率先推出该功能，将鼠标悬停在标签页上，即可预览该标签页的缩略图，该功能已默认开启，无需额外手动设置。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Chrome、Edge 等主流浏览器之前已支持标签页预览功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mozilla is rolling out a tab preview feature to its Firefox browser. The feature is currently available in Firefox Nightly, and lets users hover over a tab to see a thumbnail preview of the page. The feature is enabled by default and does not require any manual setup.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Other major browsers, such as Chrome and Edge, already support tab previews.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143312.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143312.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 02:52:47 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>浏览器</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Netflix 终止支持第二代和第三代 Apple TV</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netflix 宣布将于 7 月 31 日终止对第二代和第三代 Apple TV 机型的支持。&lt;/strong&gt;这些设备已有十多年的历史了，苹果公司也已很久未对这些型号提供支持。这两款机型都早于 tvOS 及其 App Store，因此预装了一系列应用程序。苹果于 2016 年为第三代 Apple TV 发布了最后一次更新。Netflix 将继续支持 2015 款 Apple TV HD 和 Apple TV 4K 机型。去年底，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/140160.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Netflix 也宣布停止支持多款旧款索尼电视&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Netflix has announced that it will end support for second- and third-generation Apple TV models on July 31. These devices are over a decade old, and Apple has not provided support for them in years. Both models predate tvOS and its App Store, instead featuring a collection of pre-installed apps. Apple released its last update for the third-generation Apple TV in 2016. Netflix will continue to support the 2015 Apple TV HD and Apple TV 4K. Late last year, Netflix also announced that it was dropping support for several older Sony TVs.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143293.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143293.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 02:15:35 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>