<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Apr 2024 16:32:54 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>1</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Vivaldi 浏览器发布了 Windows Arm 预览版</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Vivaldi 浏览器发布了适用于 Windows Arm 芯片的版本。&lt;/strong&gt;这是一个预览版本，尚未纳入 Vivaldi 的自动化测试系统，仅在一台硬件上进行了 「轻微测试」。因此官方提示可能存在严重问题。Google 早些时候已经发布了基于 Arm64 架构的 Chromium 版本，而 Vivaldi 的 Arm 版正是基于这个版本开发的。目前基于 Arm 处理器的 Windows 计算机还很少，但预计随着高通的 Snapdragon X Elite 于今年晚些时候发布，情况将发生改变。此外，Firefox 浏览器也在尝试为 Arm 开发适用版本。Edge 和 Brave 已为 Windows Arm 提供了实验性版本。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Vivaldi browser has released a version for Windows Arm chips. This version is a preview and has not been integrated into Vivaldi’s automated testing system. It has only undergone 「limited testing」 on specific hardware. Therefore, the company cautions that there may be significant issues with the release. Google has previously released a Chromium version based on the Arm64 architecture, which Vivaldi’s Arm version is built upon. Currently, there are relatively few computers running Windows on Arm processors, but it is expected to change with the release of Qualcomm’s Snapdragon X Elite later this year. Additionally, Firefox browser is also attempting to develop a compatible version for Arm. Edge and Brave have already provided experimental versions for Windows Arm.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142800.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142800.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:04:01 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>浏览器</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>曝大众汽车曾遭黑客攻击长达数年</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，大众汽车对德媒《明镜周刊》（Der Spiegel）承认，&lt;strong&gt;2010 年至 2015 年期间，黑客一直能够访问这家汽车的 IT 系统，且已有 19,000 份文件被盗。&lt;/strong&gt;这次网络攻击始于 2010 年。黑客首先分析了大众汽车的 IT 系统，以找出可能的弱点。2011 年，黑客开始窃取数据和文件，且接下来的几年中未被察觉。2013 年，黑客成功获得管理员权限，进一步深入大众汽车的 IT 系统，超过 19,000 份文件被盗，涉及有关汽油发动机、变速器、双离合器传动系统、电动汽车技术和燃料电池等方面的信息。直到 2014 年 6 月初，大众汽车才注意遭到攻击，该公司随后组建了一个安全团队监视黑客并采取必要的措施。德国媒体称，黑客的 IP 地址似乎指向中国，并且黑客的活动总是在特定的时间（下午 4 点）停止，似乎有着固定的办公时间。大众汽车确认了这次黑客攻击。并强调攻击发生在十多年前，之后公司已提升了 IT 系统的安全性，但大众没有披露其他细节。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Volkswagen has acknowledged to the German magazine Der Spiegel that hackers had access to the company’s IT systems between 2010 and 2015, resulting in the theft of 19,000 documents. The cyberattack began in 2010 when hackers analyzed Volkswagen’s IT systems to identify potential vulnerabilities. In 2011, they started stealing data and documents, remaining undetected for several years. By 2013, the hackers had gained administrator privileges, allowing them to penetrate deeper into Volkswagen’s IT systems. Over 19,000 documents were stolen, including information related to gasoline engines, transmissions, dual-clutch systems, electric vehicle technology, and fuel cells. It wasn’t until early June 2014 that Volkswagen noticed the attack after the hackers allegedly made a typing error. This error caused a sudden increase in the IT systems’ capacity requirements, raising suspicion. Volkswagen subsequently formed a security team to monitor the hackers and implement necessary measures.According to German media reports, it was possible to analyze the hackers’ IP addresses, which appeared to originate from China. The hackers also consistently ceased their activities at a specific time, reportedly corresponding to 4:00 PM in the Asian country, leading news outlets to speculate that they were Chinese state-sponsored hackers with regular office hours.Volkswagen has confirmed the hack, emphasizing that the incident occurred more than a decade ago and that the company has since improved its IT system security. The German automaker has not provided further details at this time.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142793.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142793.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:55:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>传 Android 15 可显示存储芯片的寿命</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，Android 开源项目（AOSP）代码库中的提交显示，&lt;strong&gt;Android 15 可能会显示 Android 手机的 UFS 存储芯片的寿命。&lt;/strong&gt;一个 API 显示，Android 15 系统设置中的一个页面将向用户显示剩余的存储芯片寿命。该 API 已添加到 Android 15 的最新 Beta 版中。由于 Google 并未要求手机厂商向操作系统共享有关 UFS 芯片的信息，因此该功能可能仅适用于部分手机。随着时间推移，智能手机存储芯片会逐渐退化，可能导致内部存储中的数据损坏或存储完全无法读取。新功能将允许用户监控存储芯片的健康状态。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;A commit in the Android Open Source Project (AOSP) code repository indicates that Android 15 may feature the ability to display the lifespan of UFS storage chips in Android phones. An API reveals that a page in the Android 15 system settings will show users the remaining lifespan of their storage chips. This API has been added to the latest beta version of Android 15. Since Google does not require smartphone manufacturers to share information about UFS chips with the operating system, this feature may only be available on certain phones. Over time, storage chips in smartphones degrade, potentially leading to data corruption or complete unreadability of the internal storage. This new feature will allow users to monitor the health status of their storage chips.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142789.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142789.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:43:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Thunderbird 将支持 Microsoft Exchange 协议</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;Mozilla Thunderbird 将于 7 月份原生支持 Microsoft Exchange 电子邮件协议。&lt;/strong&gt;这是 Mozilla 首次向该电子邮件客户端添加新协议，这也是 Thunderbird 的下一个稳定版本。据悉，之后还将添加对日历和通讯录的支持。Thunderbird 开发团队已开始将 Rust 组件整合到 Thunderbird 的代码库中。添加新协议是一项相当大的工程——目前，这个邮件客户端主要由旧的 C++代码构成，因此开发人员无法集成 Microsoft Exchange Web Services API。通过使用 Rust 编程语言，这一问题将得到解决。考虑到工作量，最初只会添加对 Exchange 电邮协议的支持，后续才会支持日历和通讯录。此前，通过第三方的附加组件，已可实现使用 Thunderbird 来访问 Exchange 账户。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;值得注意的是，微软将于 2026 年 10 月 1 日停止对 Exchange Online 和 Office 365 的 Exchange Web Services API 的支持。这意味着在两年后，Thunderbird 中的 Exchange 支持将不再适用于由微软托管的 Exchange 账户，只适用于组织自己管理的 Exchange 服务器。目前还不清楚 Thunderbird 团队是否会在此之前转向 Graph API，以实现这一功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Mozilla Thunderbird will natively support the Microsoft Exchange email protocol starting in July. This marks the first time that Mozilla has added a new protocol to its email client, and it will be included in the next stable version of Thunderbird. Support for calendar and address book integration will also be added later. The Thunderbird development team has begun integrating Rust components into the codebase of Thunderbird. Currently, the mail client is mostly comprised of old C++ code, which prevented the integration of the Microsoft Exchange Web Services API. By utilizing the Rust programming language, this limitation can be overcome. Initially, the focus will be on adding support for Exchange email protocol, with calendar and address book support to follow at a later date. Previously, it was possible to access Exchange accounts through Thunderbird using third-party add-ons. However, native support for Exchange accounts was not built into the client. It is worth noting that Microsoft will end support for the Exchange Web Services API for Exchange Online and Office 365 on October 1, 2026. This means that in two years’ time, Thunderbird’s Exchange support will no longer work for Exchange accounts hosted by Microsoft, but only for Exchange servers managed by organizations themselves. It is currently unclear whether the Thunderbird team will transition to the Graph API before that time to enable continued functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142782.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142782.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:33:56 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>办公/生产力</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>微软商店官网已允许下载独立的.exe 安装包</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/20240421232430.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，微软商店推出重要改进——&lt;strong&gt;Windows 用户现在可以直接从 Microsoft Store 网站下载独立的.exe 文件。&lt;/strong&gt;该网站不再要求与已安装的 Windows Store 应用程序进行链接，并提供独立的.exe 文件。微软已对该功能进行了长达 5 个月的测试。现在，即使卸载了微软商店应用程序，用户仍可通过.exe 文件安装软件。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft Store has introduced a significant improvement – Windows users can now directly download standalone .exe files from the Microsoft Store website. The website no longer requires a link to the installed Windows Store application and offers independent .exe files. Microsoft has conducted extensive testing of this feature for a period of five months. Now, even if the Microsoft Store application is uninstalled, users can still install software through .exe files.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142772.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142772.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 15:26:16 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>系统工具</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>