<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 16:41:32 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Google Play 将支持请他人为应用购买付款</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/05/1716644737_google-play-store-ask-someone-else-payment-button_story.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Google Play 应用商店将允许其他人为你的应用购买付款。&lt;/strong&gt;为此该商店新增了一个 「要求其他人为此项目付款」 按钮。在 Play 商店购买应用或游戏时，用户可邀请朋友或家人为想要的应用付费，付款人需要在 24 小时内对生成的支付链接付款，之后链接将过期。点击该按钮的用户会收到警告，因为付款人需要知道 TA 的电子邮件地址，以及想购买的商品。该按钮率先在印度推出，预计很快会出现在其他地区。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The Google Play app store now allows others to make purchases and payments for your apps. To enable this feature, the store has introduced a 「Request payment from others」 button. When purchasing apps or games on the Play Store, users can invite friends or family to pay for the desired apps. This button was initially launched in India and is expected to roll out to other regions soon. Users who click on this button will receive a warning, as the payer will need to know their email address and the item they wish to purchase. The payer must make the payment within 24 hours of receiving the generated payment link, as the link will expire thereafter.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143122.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143122.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 11:10:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>阿里巴巴正对淘宝频繁改版</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐持续跟踪发现，&lt;strong&gt;阿里巴巴正在对淘宝客户端进行频繁的改版尝试。&lt;/strong&gt;改版似乎正朝着更加紧凑、清爽、简单的方向进行，这体现在淘宝 App 首页（推荐）、个人中心、商品搜索页等多处。在我们的多台测试设备上，同一版本的淘宝客户端的界面呈现各不相同，淘宝正针对不同用户测试不同的改版方案。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;本月初，淘宝还称&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142943.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;全面重启对淘宝 PC 站的优化工作，以及重开淘宝论坛&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Alibaba is actively making frequent attempts to revamp the Taobao mobile app. The redesign appears to be moving towards a more compact, refreshing, and simplified direction, which is evident in various sections, including the Taobao app homepage (recommendations), personal center, and product search pages. On our multiple testing devices, the interface of the Taobao app varies among the same version, as Alibaba is testing different redesign strategies for different users.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143120.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143120.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 11:02:30 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>iOS 18 可用 AI 生成表情符号</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;科技记者 Mark Gurman 透露，&lt;strong&gt;iOS 18 将提供一个 AI 工具，允许用户生成自定义表情符号。&lt;/strong&gt;该工具不是独立的 App，它根据用户在文本框中输入的内容直接生成表情符号。此外，语音助手 Siri 将借助 AI 技术让发音更加自然，并且将有可能自定义应用图标的颜色。用户可将这些图标放置在自定义的位置，而不局限于 iOS 应用网格的固定顺序。该公司还希望将 Siri 用到的 AI 技术应用于 Xcode，以为开发人员提供支持。苹果希望在设备本地完成大部分 AI 任务的处理，某些密集任务可能会通过云端处理。这些云计算使用的是 M2 Ultra 芯片，能够以隐私友好的方式处理数据。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Tech journalist Mark Gurman revealed that iOS 18 will feature an AI tool that allows users to generate custom emojis. This functionality will not be a separate app; instead, it will generate emojis based on the user’s input in a text box. Additionally, the voice assistant Siri will sound more natural thanks to AI technology, and there will be the possibility to customize the color of app icons. Users will also have the ability to place these icons in custom locations rather than being restricted to a fixed order in the iOS app grid. The company also intends to apply the AI technology used by Siri to Xcode, providing support for developers. Apple aims to process the majority of AI tasks on the device itself, while some intensive tasks may be processed in the cloud. These cloud computations will utilize the M2 Ultra chip, which can handle data in a privacy-friendly manner.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143112.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143112.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:41:22 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>苹果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>英国 2026 年起允许自动驾驶汽车上路</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;近日，英国通过了法案 Automated Vehicles Bill，根据该法案，&lt;strong&gt;从 2026 年开始，完全自动驾驶的车辆将被允许在英国的公共道路上行驶&lt;/strong&gt;。车辆中仍需要有一名驾驶员，但在自动驾驶模式下，驾驶员不再对车辆的行为负责。前提是这些车辆 「在自动驾驶模式下与谨慎和能干的人类驾驶员一样安全或更安全」。为此，政府计划建立一个 「批准制度」，并设立一个 「独立的事故调查职能」。当局称企业必须履行持续的义务，以确保其车辆的安全性。英国政府认为，自动驾驶车辆可提高交通的可访问性，因为不会开车的人也可以上路了。英国交通部长马克·哈珀（Mark Harper）将该法案的批准是 「对安全和经济的巨大推动」。预计到 2035 年，自动驾驶汽车行业的价值将达到 420 亿英镑（480 亿欧元），并创造 38,000 个就业机会。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Recently, the United Kingdom passed the Automated Vehicles Bill, which allows fully autonomous vehicles to operate on public roads starting from 2026. While a driver is still required to be present in the vehicle, they are no longer responsible for the vehicle’s behavior in autonomous mode. The condition is that these vehicles must be 「as safe as or safer than cautious and competent human drivers」 in autonomous mode. The government plans to establish an approval system and create an independent incident investigation function. Companies are required to fulfill ongoing obligations to ensure the safety of their vehicles. The UK government believes that autonomous vehicles can improve transportation accessibility, as even individuals who cannot drive can now take to the roads. The approval of the bill by the UK Transport Minister, Mark Harper, is seen as a significant boost for both safety and the economy. It is estimated that by 2035, the autonomous vehicle industry could be worth £42 billion (€48 billion) and create 38,000 jobs.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143106.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143106.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 10:30:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>