<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>软餐 - 新鲜软件资讯 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 16:43:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Google One 的 VPN 服务下月将关停</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;谷歌将于 6 月 20 日停止其云存储应用程序 Google One 的 VPN 服务。&lt;/strong&gt;谷歌在 4 月份宣布将停止该服务，当时该公司称对 VPN 服务没有足够的兴趣。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pixel 8 及更新版本的设备默认内置 VPN。对于这些用户来说影响不大。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Pixel 7、7 Pro、7a 和 Fold 还没有内置 VPN。这些设备将从 6 月 3 日起收到系统更新，以激活内置的 VPN 服务。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;其他设备用户将无法继续使用 Google One VPN，这些用户会被重定向到 Google 支持页面上的其他 VPN 服务。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143043.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143043.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 03:00:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>网络应用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>硅谷兴起「爱国主义风潮」</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;华尔街日报说，硅谷投资界正在兴起一股 「爱国主义风潮」。&lt;/strong&gt;投资者对美国国防领域的资金投入激增。曾帮助 Facebook、Google 等科技公司起步的投资者们正转向支持初创企业开发战场软件、军用无人机和自动驾驶潜水艇等领域。这种转变与中美关系近年来的明显变化有关。风投人士正适应这种转变。需要知道的是，硅谷投资者们并非单纯因爱国而投资，而是因为这类投资能获得丰厚回报。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to The Wall Street Journal, there is a growing trend of 「patriotic investing」 in Silicon Valley’s investment community. Investors are significantly increasing their funding in the U.S. defense sector. Investors who previously supported tech companies like Facebook and Google are now shifting towards supporting startups developing battlefield software, military drones, and autonomous submarines. This shift is attributed to the noticeable changes in U.S.-China relations in recent years. Venture capitalists are adapting to this transformation. It is important to note that Silicon Valley investors are not solely driven by patriotism but rather by the potential for substantial returns on these types of investments.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143038.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143038.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 10:40:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Edge 浏览器修复了两个安全漏洞</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;微软于刚刚过去的周末为 Microsoft Edge 124 发布了安全更新（124.0.2478.97）。&lt;/strong&gt;此次更新修复了两个安全漏洞，分别是 CVE-2024-30055 和 CVE-2024-30055，前者允许远程攻击者通过特制的 HTML 页面利用堆损坏，后者是 Microsoft Edge 独有的低严重性欺骗漏洞。两个漏洞均已被野外利用，因此 Edge 用户应尽快安装更新。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has recently released a security update (version 124.0.2478.97) for Microsoft Edge 124 over the past weekend. This update addresses two security vulnerabilities, namely CVE-2024-30055 and CVE-2024-30055. The first vulnerability allows remote attackers to exploit heap corruption using specially crafted HTML pages, while the second vulnerability is a unique low severity deception vulnerability specific to Microsoft Edge. Both vulnerabilities have been exploited in the wild, so it is recommended that Edge users install the update as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143035.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143035.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 09:49:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
            <category>浏览器</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>衞星互联网 Starlink 今年有望实现盈利</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SpaceX 旗下的衞星互联网业务 Starlink（星链）有望在 2024 年实现盈利。&lt;/strong&gt;研究机构 Quilty Space 估计，Starlink 在全球拥有近 300 万客户，今年的收入将达到 66 亿美元，自由现金流估计为 6 亿美元，这将是 SpaceX 首次实现盈利。SpaceX 于 2019 年 5 月发射了第一批 60 颗 Starlink V0.9 衞星，截至目前共发射了 6,300 多颗衞星，最后一批衞星将于本周被送入轨道。SpaceX 通过其可重复使用的猎鹰 9 号火箭发射衞星，可大幅降低成本。未来巨型星际飞船火箭投用后，还将允许把大型 Starlink 衞星放置在轨道上，以提供不依赖用户终端的直接到小区的连接。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SpaceX’s satellite internet service, Starlink, is expected to become profitable in 2024. Research firm Quilty Space estimates that Starlink has nearly 3 million customers worldwide, with projected revenues of $6.6 billion this year and an estimated free cash flow of $600 million. This would mark the first time SpaceX achieves profitability in its relatively short history. SpaceX launched its first batch of 60 Starlink V0.9 satellites in May 2019 and has since launched over 6,300 satellites. The final batch of satellites is set to be deployed into orbit this week. SpaceX’s reusable Falcon 9 rockets significantly reduce costs for satellite launches. In the future, the deployment of the giant Starship spacecraft will allow for the placement of large Starlink satellites in orbit, providing direct connectivity to communities without relying on user terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143029.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143029.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 09:44:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Edge 浏览器将获得 AI 主题生成器</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;软餐获悉，&lt;strong&gt;微软打算为 Edge 浏览器推出一个基于 AI 的主题生成器。&lt;/strong&gt;用户输入文本提示词，Edge 即可生成一系列图像，并可设置为浏览器主题，包括图像的主色调也可作用于浏览器框架。该功能计划 6 月份发布。组织管理员可使用 「AIGenThemesEnabled」 策略来限制 AI 主题生成功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft plans to introduce an AI-based theme generator for the Edge browser. Users can input text prompts, and Edge will generate a series of images that can be set as browser themes. The main color tones of the images can also be applied to the browser frame. This feature is scheduled for release in June. Organizational administrators can use the 「AIGenThemesEnabled」 policy to restrict the AI theme generation functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143025.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143025.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 09:31:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>业界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>