<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 14:59:25 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Netflix 宣佈將推出《我的世界》動畫劇集</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netflix 宣佈將推出一部圍繞視頻遊戲 Minecraft（我的世界）的動畫劇集。&lt;/strong&gt;這家流媒體平台提到了一個 「帶有全新角色的原創故事」。發佈日期尚未公佈。已釋出的預告片展示了下界與爬行者的地下世界。這部劇集由加拿大工作室 WildBrain Studios 製作，該機構曾為 Netflix 製作過幾部兒童劇集和《Sonic Prime》。此外，還有一部 Minecraft 主題電影正在開發中，傑克·布萊克（Jack Black）可能會扮演主角。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Netflix has announced the upcoming release of an animated series based on the video game Minecraft. The streaming platform mentions an 「original story with new characters.」 The release date has not been revealed yet. The teaser trailer showcases the Nether, an underground world, and a Creeper. There is no indication of the plot at this time. The animated series is being produced by Canadian studio WildBrain Studios, known for creating several children’s series and 「Sonic Prime」 for Netflix. Additionally, there is an ongoing development of a Minecraft-themed film, with actor Jack Black rumored to have a leading role.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143204.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143204.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:22:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Via 瀏覽器更新，新增複製標籤頁功能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;以輕快簡潔見長的 Via 瀏覽器最近發佈了最新版本 Via Browser 5.6.1。&lt;/strong&gt;該版本推出了多項新功能及改進。其中帶來了 「標籤頁菜單複製標籤」 功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Play 商店：&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mark.via.gp&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=mark.via.gp&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;– 標籤頁菜單新增複製標籤選項&lt;br&gt;– 主菜單新增其它應用打開選項&lt;br&gt;– 優化用戶腳本的兼容性&lt;br&gt;– 腳本支持 data 協議的依賴資源&lt;br&gt;– 修復閲讀模式下打印頁面異常的錯誤&lt;br&gt;– 修復過濾規則可能被錯誤清空的問題&lt;br&gt;– 其它錯誤修復&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143187.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143187.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 11:58:28 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>蘋果 Apple TV+正開發安卓版本</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;蘋果發佈的招聘信息顯示，該公司計劃將 Apple TV+服務引入 Android 手機和平板電腦。&lt;/strong&gt;蘋果正在尋找一位 Android 工程師，負責開發一款 「被數百萬用戶用來觀看電視和體育賽事」 的應用程序。Apple TV+已在搭載 Google TV 的 Chromecast 和運行 Android 系統的智能電視上可用，但尚未支持 Android 手機和平板電腦。目前只有少數幾款蘋果應用程序為 Android 推出了適用版本，例如 Apple Music、Beats 和 Move to iOS 等。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Bloomberg: Apple is planning to bring its Apple TV+ service to Android phones and tablets. According to a job listing released by the company, Apple is seeking an Android engineer to develop an application 「used by millions to watch TV and sports.」 While Apple TV+ is already available on devices such as Google TV-powered Chromecast and Android-based smart TVs, it currently lacks support for Android phones and tablets. Apple’s decision to develop apps for other operating systems is uncommon, with only a few Apple applications, such as Apple Music, Beats, and Move to iOS, having versions available for Android. The timing of when the TV+ app will become available for Android phones remains unclear.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143166.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143166.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 30 May 2024 08:28:37 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>蘋果</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Windows Copilot 已被集成到微軟桌面</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;微軟的人工智能助理應用 Windows Copilot 已被集成到微軟桌面（Microsoft Launcher）的最新 Beta 版中。&lt;/strong&gt;Google Play（&lt;a href=&quot;https://play.google.com/store/apps/details?id=com.microsoft.launcher&amp;amp;hl=en-US&amp;amp;ah=8cxnoy1ug9VptVgQxqniZsdMMbM&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;鏈接&lt;/a&gt;）已經上架了這個版本。與此同時舊版的 Bing Chat 圖標已被 Copilot 取代。因為微軟已經放棄了 Bing Chat 品牌。需要指出，微軟桌面中的 Copilot 功能有限，不包含 Copilot Pro 的假期計劃、烹飪助手、健身教練和筆記本等功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft’s artificial intelligence assistant application, Windows Copilot, has been integrated into the latest beta version of Microsoft Launcher. This version is now available on Google Play (link). Additionally, the old Bing Chat icon has been replaced by Copilot, as Microsoft has discontinued the Bing Chat brand. It should be noted that the Copilot functionality in Microsoft Launcher is limited and does not include features such as Copilot Pro’s vacation planner, cooking assistant, fitness coach, and notebook.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143128.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143128.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 08:31:12 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>油管迎來「聽歌識曲」功能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;谷歌為 YouTube 和 YouTube Music 的安卓版本推出了類似 Shazam 的聽歌識曲功能。&lt;/strong&gt;用戶可通過哼唱、吹口哨或播放錄音來讓 YouTube 識別歌曲。在兩款應用的搜索欄右側的麥克風圖標旁可以訪問該功能。暫不清楚谷歌何時會將該功能向 iOS 用戶推出。2020 年，谷歌向 Google Assistent 引入了類似的功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google has introduced a Shazam-like song recognition feature for the Android versions of YouTube and YouTube Music. Users can identify songs on YouTube by humming, whistling, or playing a recording. The feature is accessible through the microphone icon next to the search bar in both applications. It is currently unknown when Google will release this feature for iOS users. In 2020, Google introduced a similar feature to Google Assistant.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143126.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143126.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 28 May 2024 08:21:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓應用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>