<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 27 Apr 2024 16:36:29 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>1</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>[觀點] 社交媒體上的反智賬號越來越多了</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-wpcom-alert&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info block-alert&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文來自特邀作者，文中觀點不代表本站。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;本站特邀作者/假不假&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/GL0nSvYXgAEQ3kP.jpg&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;社交媒體上的反智賬號越來越多了。比如，最近微博上一個名不見經傳的賬號 「@兔頭學姐張鐵根」 發帖稱，「網絡上的 LGBT、女拳等等問題，都屬於歐美話語體下的議題侵蝕，底層思維仍然是資產階級特有的個人主義……對於長期、多次、屢教不改者追究其刑事和民事責任」 云云。引發熱議。這位博主在帖子中還稱 「這次來北京開會，突然對以後樂觀了一些」「透露一些吧，我撿能説的聊聊」 等，煞有介事，似乎該賬號代表 「某個部門」，抑或獲得了 「某種授權」。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;實際情況是，這則貼文在互聯網上流傳後，已遭刪除。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;翻閲該賬號，多為邏輯混亂、不知所云的貼文。甚至連貴為中央媒體前負責人的胡錫進也被該賬號評論為 「玩文字遊戲或者導向有問題」。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;我們建議該賬號認證為 「微博搞笑博主」。&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142882.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142882.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 07:20:39 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Telegram 稱未受到 App Store 中國區下架事件影響</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Telegram 創始人帕維爾·杜羅夫（Pavel Durov）稱，Telegram 沒有受到被 App Store 中國區下架一事的影響。&lt;/strong&gt;上週，&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142763.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;App Store 中國區商店中下架了 WhatsApp、Threads、Telegram 和 Signal 等多款應用&lt;/a&gt;。Pavel Durov 表示，沒有看到 Telegram 在中國下載量減少的跡象。他聲稱 Telegram 在中國是 Google Play 下載量最多的移動應用程序。Pavel Durov 還認為，相比於 Android 用戶支持側載應用程序的特性，iPhone 處於劣勢，其在中國的市場份額將繼續縮小，蘋果正因其在應用程序上的封閉政策 「自食苦果」。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Telegram founder Pavel Durov stated that Telegram has not been affected by the removal from the Chinese App Store. He mentioned that there have been no signs of decreased downloads for Telegram in China. He claimed that Telegram is the most downloaded mobile app on Google Play in China. Pavel Durov also believes that iPhones are at a disadvantage compared to Android users who support sideloading applications, and as a result, the market share of iPhones in China will continue to shrink. Apple is experiencing the consequences of its closed policies regarding applications.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142831.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142831.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 23 Apr 2024 06:07:17 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>字節跳動賣掉 TikTok 幾成定局</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-wpcom-alert&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info block-alert&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本站對所刊之內容保持中立，不持立場。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;上週六，美國眾議院以 360 票贊成、58 票反對的壓倒性優勢通過了一項強制字節跳動出售其短視頻應用程序 TikTok 或者禁用該應用的法案。&lt;/strong&gt;在該法案下，字節跳動將有 1 年時間來出售 TikTok，如果字節跳動無法如期找到買家，TikTok 將被美國政府禁用。該應用在美國擁有 1.7 億用戶。未來幾天，美國參議院可能對該法案進行表決。總統拜登表示，他將簽署該法案使之生效。此外媒體報道稱，TikTok 和字節跳動的首席法律顧問 Erich Andersen 計劃離職。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Last Saturday, the United States House of Representatives overwhelmingly passed a bill with 360 votes in favor and 58 votes against, which would require ByteDance to sell its short video application TikTok or face a ban on the app. Under this legislation, ByteDance would have one year to sell TikTok, and if they fail to find a buyer within that timeframe, the app would be banned by the U.S. government. TikTok currently boasts 170 million users in the United States. In the coming days, the bill may be voted on by the U.S. Senate. President Biden has stated that he will sign the bill into law. Additionally, media reports indicate that TikTok and ByteDance’s Chief Legal Officer, Erich Andersen, plan to resign.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142824.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142824.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:49:00 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Win11 鏡像精簡工具 Tiny11 Builder 更新了</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;可將 Windows 11 原版鏡像精簡為輕量版系統的開源工具 Tiny11 Builder 更新了。&lt;/strong&gt;Tiny11 Builder 可根據用戶的偏好創建定製版的 Windows 11 鏡像，是現成的 &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/?s=Tiny11&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;Tiny11&lt;/a&gt; 之外的新選擇，適合動手能力強的讀者。可參考我們&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/121081.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;較早前的介紹&lt;/a&gt;。本次更新後的 Tiny11 Builder 使用了 PowerShell，用戶應在使用該項目之前將執行策略設置為無限制。請以管理員身份運行 PowerShell，並執行 Set-ExecutionPolicy unrestricted 命令。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/ntdevlabs/tiny11builder&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;從 GitHub 存儲庫下載 Tiny11 Builder&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The open-source tool Tiny11 Builder, which allows for the customization of Windows 11 images by reducing unnecessary components, has been updated. Users can create a tailored version of Windows 11 based on their preferences using Tiny11 Builder, providing an alternative to the pre-existing Tiny11 option. This tool is suitable for readers with advanced technical skills. Please refer to our earlier introduction for more details. The updated version of Tiny11 Builder now utilizes PowerShell, and users are advised to set the execution policy to unrestricted prior to using the project. To do so, run PowerShell as an administrator and execute the command 「Set-ExecutionPolicy unrestricted.」&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142818.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142818.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 22 Apr 2024 06:34:36 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
            <category>系統工具</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>真假難辨：微軟 AI 模型 VASA-1 讓照片開口唱歌</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/04/2024042116082237.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;微軟推出的最新 AI 模型 VASA-1 可將肖像照片與音頻文件進行關聯，並生成視頻，使照片能夠以 「逼真的方式説話和唱歌」。&lt;/strong&gt;微軟分享了演示視頻（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.microsoft.com/en-us/research/project/vasa-1/&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;圍觀地址&lt;/a&gt;），包括蒙娜麗莎説唱的視頻。使用該模型的用戶可以自行調整頭部運動或視線方向等參數。在離線模式下，VASA-1 能夠以 512×512 像素、45fps 的幀數生成視頻，其在線版本中支持最高 40fps。微軟稱：「VASA-1 能夠產生與音頻完美同步的脣部動作。它還能捕捉到廣泛的微妙面部表情和自然的頭部運動，這有助於提高真實感和生動性的感知。」VASA-1 模型主要用於虛擬角色的設計。&lt;strong&gt;微軟強調，出於對該 AI 模型被用於製作深度偽造的擔憂，該公司沒有計劃將 VASA-1 投放市場&lt;/strong&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has introduced its latest AI model, VASA-1, which allows for the association of portrait photos with audio files and generates videos that make the photos 「speak and sing in a realistic manner.」 Microsoft has shared demonstration videos, including one featuring the Mona Lisa rapping. Users of the model can make adjustments to parameters such as head movements and gaze direction. In offline mode, VASA-1 can generate videos at a resolution of 512×512 pixels and a frame rate of 45fps, while the online version supports up to 40fps. Microsoft states that 「VASA-1 can produce lip movements perfectly synchronized with the audio. It can also capture a wide range of subtle facial expressions and natural head movements, enhancing the perception of authenticity and liveliness.」 The VASA-1 model is primarily designed for the creation of virtual characters. Microsoft emphasizes that due to concerns about potential misuse for deepfakes, they have no plans to release VASA-1 to the market.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142808.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142808.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 21 Apr 2024 16:13:48 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>