<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Sat, 08 Jun 2024 19:32:41 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>微軟宣佈重啓 Win10 Beta 通道，將發佈新功能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;微軟正在重新開放 Windows 10 的 Beta 頻道，並稱將為 Win10 提供 「新功能和更多改進」。&lt;/strong&gt;微軟將在未來幾周內發佈第一個新的 Beta 版本。此舉令人意外，因為微軟一年前已宣佈 Windows 10 不再獲得任何新功能。通過 Beta 頻道，Windows 10 用戶可以繼續留在 Windows 10，而不是升級到 Windows 11。不過，Windows 10 的終止時間不會因為 Beta 頻道的 「復活」 而改變，它將於 2025 年 10 月 14 日退出歷史舞台。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft is reopening the Beta Channel for Windows 10, saying it will give the software 「new features and further improvements.」 Microsoft will release its first new Beta build in the coming weeks. The move is a surprise, coming a year after Microsoft said that Windows 10 would no longer receive new features. The Beta Channel gives Windows 10 users a way to keep using Windows 10 instead of upgrading to Windows 11 . However, the end-of-support date for Windows 10 won’t change as a result of the Beta Channel’s resurrection: it’s still scheduled to be retired on October 14, 2025.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143315.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143315.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 03:00:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 10</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>X（Twitter）對成人內容放寬政策</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-wpcom-alert&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info block-alert&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文是客觀報道，本站及作者對報道對象不持立場。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;X（Twitter）似乎決定針對成人內容放寬政策。&lt;/strong&gt;因為該平台最近發佈了一個新的成人內容政策頁面。頁面顯示，X 用戶現在可以發佈帶有 「成人裸體或性行為」 的內容，但將有一些限制。該平台認為此類內容 「可以成為一種合法的藝術表達形式」。與此同時，X 將針對這些內容覆蓋內容警告信息，未登記生日的未成年用戶將無法通過內容警告以瀏覽這些內容。X 賬戶頭像或橫幅中也禁止放置成人內容。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;這並不意味着 X 允許任何成人內容，因為該平台仍然禁止任何可以標記為 「剝削、未經同意、物化、性化或傷害未成年人以及淫穢行為」 的成人內容。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;這次同時發佈的還有一個新的暴力內容政策頁面。X 官方表示，這兩個新政策頁面都取代了其以前的敏感媒體和暴力言論政策。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;X (Twitter) appears to have decided to relax its policies against adult content. The platform recently published a new adult content policy page , which reveals that X users are now able to post content that features 「nudity or sexual activity」 so long as certain restrictions are met. The platform believes that such content 「can be a legitimate form of artistic expression.」 X will, however, cover such content with an interstitial warning, and underage users who have not registered their birthday will not be able to proceed past the warning to view the content. Adult content will also be prohibited in X account profile pictures and banners. This doesn’t mean that X will allow any adult content, as the platform will still ban any adult content that could be flagged as 「exploitative, non-consensual, objectifying, dehumanizing or grooming minors, as well as pornography.」 Also rolling out today is a new support page for its violent content policy . 「These new policy pages replace our previous Sensitive Media and Violent Speech policies,」 an X spokesperson says.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143270.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143270.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[清單] 2024 年 5 月 Telegram 更新要點</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，Telegram（電報）於上個月底發佈了 2024 年 5 月份的版本更新。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;我們從冗長的更新日誌中梳理了更新要點。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.org/blog/message-effects-and-more#message-effects&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;私聊消息動畫效果&lt;/strong&gt;。現在，Telegram 私聊消息可以動畫效果發送，對方打開聊天時會播放這些效果。Telegram 免費提供 6 種效果，Telegram Premium 用戶可解鎖數百種效果。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;媒體上方的字幕。&lt;/strong&gt;標題現在可移動到媒體上方。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;手機號碼的快速操作&lt;/strong&gt;。在聊天中點擊手機號碼會打開新菜單，可快速發送消息、通話或將號碼添加為聯繫人。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;主題標籤搜索&lt;/strong&gt;。現在，在任何聊天中點擊主題標籤可顯示來自公共頻道的搜索結果。例如快速找到頻 &lt;code&gt;#news&lt;/code&gt;&amp;nbsp; 或 &lt;code&gt;#travel&lt;/code&gt;&amp;nbsp; 視頻。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;可摺疊的引用&lt;/strong&gt;。現在可將文本片段隱藏在摺疊的引用塊中，消息更緊湊。只需添加引用格式，並在輸入框中點擊摺疊按鈕。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS 上的彩色通話&lt;/strong&gt;。現在，Telegram 原生 macOS 應用程序用戶可使用彩色通話界面，包括動態背景和時尚動畫。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143243.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143243.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 15:00:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>特朗普入駐 TikTok</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;共和黨總統候選人特朗普 (Donald Trump) 入駐了短視頻平台 TikTok。&lt;/strong&gt;該賬號在週日早間粉絲超過 80 萬。上週六晚，特朗普發佈一段了 13 秒的短視頻，是他在新澤西州紐瓦克的終極格鬥冠軍賽（簡稱 UFC) 活動的視頻。視頻中，特朗普在賽場內向粉絲致意。特朗普希望通過加入 TikTok 來拉攏年輕選民。而就在四年前，特朗普在總統任上曾試圖下令封禁 TikTok，但因法律問題未能如願。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has joined the short video platform TikTok. The account garnered over 800,000 followers on Sunday morning. Last Saturday night, Trump released a 13-second video showcasing his presence at the Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) event in Newark, New Jersey. In the video, Trump greeted his fans inside the arena. By joining TikTok, Trump aims to attract young voters. Interestingly, just four years ago, during his presidency, Trump attempted to ban TikTok, but his efforts were hindered by legal challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143241.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143241.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:54:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Cloud 推出條件寬鬆的 90 天試用計劃</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，谷歌雲（Google Cloud）為了推廣 Vertex AI，日前推出了免費試用計劃，用戶可從 Google Cloud 獲得 150 美元的贈送金，可在 3 個月內體驗 Vertex AI 及 Google Cloud，包括在 Google Cloud 上創建虛擬機。&lt;strong&gt;我們測試發現，申請這項體驗計劃無需驗證信用卡或銀行卡，甚至點擊 「免費試用 Vertex AI」 體驗按鈕，即可直接通過申請。&lt;/strong&gt;後續還可激活賬號（需驗卡）可再獲得 150 美元贈金。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;如果讀者在申請時彈出驗證信用卡或銀行卡界面，説明 IP 不滿足條件，可考慮更換一個新的 IP 再次申請。&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai?hl=zh_cn&quot;&gt;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai?hl=zh_cn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud has recently launched a free trial program to promote Vertex AI. Users can receive a $150 credit from Google Cloud to experience Vertex AI and Google Cloud services for three months, including creating virtual machines on Google Cloud. Our testing has found that applying for this trial program does not require credit card or bank card verification. Users can simply click the 「Free Trial Vertex AI」 button to apply directly. Afterward, activating the account (requires card verification) will provide an additional $150 credit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If readers encounter a credit card or bank card verification prompt during the application process, it indicates that the IP does not meet the requirements. In this case, consider changing to a new IP and reapplying.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143238.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143238.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:12:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>