<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 16:41:55 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>HBO Max 承諾為老訂戶保留 4K 和杜比權益</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;流媒體平台 HBO Max 表示，已擁有 4K 和杜比全景聲（Dolby Atmos）的 HBO Max 客戶，在 6 月 11 日新計劃上線後也將被繼續保留這兩項權益。&lt;/strong&gt;此前該公司曾表示 4K 和杜比全景聲（Dolby Atmos）僅包含在高級（premium）訂閲計劃中。HBO Max 本週早些時候宣佈了三項新的訂閲，將取代當前的訂閲。其中包括帶有廣告的基本計劃、支持 1080p 的標準訂閲以及支持 4K 和杜比全景聲的高級訂閲計劃。自 HBO Max 成立以來的訂戶將自動轉到新的標準計劃，並將保留其 50% 的折扣。該公告引發了老訂戶擔心權益 「縮水」 的擔憂，現在 HBO Max 不得不出來澄清，即新政策將僅適用於新訂戶。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;HBO Max, the streaming platform, has announced that customers who already have access to 4K and Dolby Atmos will continue to retain these benefits after the launch of their new plans on June 11th. Previously, the company had stated that 4K and Dolby Atmos were only included in the premium subscription plan. Earlier this week, HBO Max announced three new subscriptions that will replace the current ones. These include a basic plan with ads, a standard subscription supporting 1080p, and a premium subscription supporting 4K and Dolby Atmos. Subscribers since the inception of HBO Max will be automatically transitioned to the new standard plan and will retain their 50% discount. The announcement caused concerns among existing subscribers about a potential reduction in their benefits. HBO Max has now clarified that the new policy will only apply to new subscribers.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143012.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143012.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 09:36:55 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>谷歌雲誤刪了澳大利亞養老基金組織的賬戶</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;谷歌雲（Google Cloud）曝出事故——該公司上週不慎刪除了澳大利亞學術界養老基金 UniSuper 的賬戶，導致該組織在 Google Cloud 上的所有數據都被擦除，數十萬客戶無法訪問他們的財務數據。&lt;/strong&gt;谷歌雲首席執行官託馬斯·庫裏安（Thomas Kurian）在聲明中寫道，UniSuper 的帳戶發生的錯誤配置導致數據被刪除，且 Google Cloud 的兩個副本否被刪掉了。幸運的是該組織仍有另一個雲服務的備份，可通過該備份恢復數據。Google Cloud 稱這是一個獨特的事件，世界上任何地方的 Google Cloud 客戶從未遇到過此類問題。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud encountered an incident last week when it accidentally deleted the account of UniSuper, an Australian academic retirement fund, resulting in the erasure of all their data on Google Cloud. This incident left hundreds of thousands of customers unable to access their financial data. Thomas Kurian, the CEO of Google Cloud, stated in a statement that an error in the configuration of UniSuper’s account led to the deletion of the data, and two copies of the data on Google Cloud were also erased. Fortunately, the organization had a backup on another cloud service, allowing them to restore the data from that backup. Google Cloud referred to this incident as a unique event and stated that no Google Cloud customer anywhere else in the world has experienced such an issue before.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143008.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143008.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sat, 11 May 2024 09:16:33 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>中國部分用戶可直接使用 WhatsApp</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;據彭博社，&lt;strong&gt;北京和上海部分用戶稱，他們可以正常地使用此前被禁用的 WhatsApp 服務，持續時間已有兩週。&lt;/strong&gt;這些用戶可不借助其他工具直接使用 WhatsApp 軟件正常收發消息。另有用戶則表示，這可追溯到&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/142763.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;蘋果商店下架 WhatsApp 和 Threads&lt;/a&gt; 開始。尚不清楚能正常使用 WhatsApp 的用戶規模。令人頗感意外的是，WhatsApp 的代表拒絕發表評論。這幾乎暗示該公司知道更多信息。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Bloomberg, some users in Beijing and Shanghai have reported being able to use the previously disabled WhatsApp service for the past two weeks. These users are able to send and receive messages using the WhatsApp application directly without the need for any other tools. Other users have indicated that this coincides with the removal of WhatsApp and Threads from the Apple App Store. It is unclear how many users are able to use WhatsApp normally. Representatives from WhatsApp have declined to comment, which is somewhat surprising and suggests that the company may have more information regarding the situation.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142997.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142997.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 15:39:49 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>電報創始人指 Signal 的加密和開源有欺騙性</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Signal 一般被認為是一款加密消息應用，但 Telegram 創始人帕維爾·杜羅夫（Pavel Durov）不這麼看。&lt;/strong&gt;他日前援引了 Twitter 的創始人傑克·多爾西（Jack Dorsey）的一篇文章，這篇文章指出，Signal 的現任領導者是美國國務院 「負責海外政權更迭的活動人士」。美國政府花費了 300 萬美元來構建 Signal 的加密技術，如今，相同的加密技術也被應用於 WhatsApp、Facebook Messenger、Google Messages 甚至 Skype 中。看起來，美國的大型科技公司似乎不（被）允許自行構建獨立於政府幹預的加密協議。Pavel Durov 自述，一些 「重要人士」 表示他們的 Signal 消息曾 「在美國法庭或媒體中被利用」，但 Signal 對此迴應其是開源的，任何人都可以驗證。&lt;strong&gt;Pavel Durov 還指出，Signal 不允許研究人員確保他們的 GitHub 代碼與用戶 iPhone 上運行的 Signal 應用程序使用的代碼相同。Signal 拒絕為 iOS 添加可重現構建功能，並關閉了社區的 GitHub 請求。&lt;/strong&gt;Pavel Durov 宣稱 Telegram 是 「唯一一個允許每個人確保其應用程序確實使用在 Github 上發佈的相同開源代碼的流行消息服務」。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Signal is generally regarded as a secure encrypted messaging application, but Telegram founder Pavel Durov begs to differ. He recently quoted a story by Jack Dorsey, the founder of Twitter, which pointed out that the current leaders of Signal are 「activists used by the US State Department for regime change abroad.」 The US government spent $3 million to build Signal’s encryption technology, and now the same encryption technology is implemented in WhatsApp, Facebook Messenger, Google Messages, and even Skype. It seems that large tech companies in the US are not allowed to develop their own encryption protocols independent of government interference. Pavel Durov mentioned that some 「important people」 have claimed that their Signal messages were 「exploited in US courts or media,」 but Signal’s response is that they are open source, and anyone can verify their security. Pavel Durov also pointed out that Signal does not allow researchers to ensure that their GitHub code matches the code used in the Signal app on users’ iPhones. Signal refused to add reproducible builds for iOS and closed the community’s GitHub request. Pavel Durov claims that Telegram is the 「only massively popular messaging service that allows everyone to ensure that its apps indeed use the same open source code published on GitHub.」&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142963.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142963.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 09:59:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>微軟明年推出 Exchange Server 訂閲版</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;微軟公司通過官方博客證實，該公司將於明年發佈 Exchange Server 的訂閲版本，即 Exchange Server SE。&lt;/strong&gt;此版本將在 Exchange Server 2019 和 2016 的支持結束之前發佈。微軟尚未公佈訂閲價格。微軟稱，Exchange Server SE 將在 2025 年第三季度初推出。在此之前，Exchange Server 2019 將收到其第 15 個也是最後一個累積更新（CU）。訂閲版在代碼上將與此 Exchange Server 2019 CU15 相同，因此保留了相同的系統要求。最初唯一的區別涉及許可協議、名稱以及版本號。微軟每年將為 Exchange Server SE 發佈兩次累積更新。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has confirmed through an official blog post that the company will release a subscription version of Exchange Server next year, known as Exchange Server SE. This version will be released before the support for Exchange Server 2019 and 2016 ends. Microsoft has not yet disclosed the subscription pricing. Microsoft states that Exchange Server SE will be launched in the early third quarter of 2025. Prior to that, Exchange Server 2019 will receive its 15th and final cumulative update (CU). The subscription version will have the same codebase as Exchange Server 2019 CU15. Therefore, SE retains the same system requirements. The initial and only difference lies in the licensing agreement, name, and version number. Microsoft will release two cumulative updates per year for Exchange Server SE.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/142953.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/142953.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 10 May 2024 05:09:10 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>辦公/生產力</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>