<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 16:43:12 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>120</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Google One 的 VPN 服務下月將關停</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;谷歌將於 6 月 20 日停止其雲存儲應用程序 Google One 的 VPN 服務。&lt;/strong&gt;谷歌在 4 月份宣佈將停止該服務，當時該公司稱對 VPN 服務沒有足夠的興趣。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Pixel 8 及更新版本的設備默認內置 VPN。對於這些用戶來説影響不大。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Pixel 7、7 Pro、7a 和 Fold 還沒有內置 VPN。這些設備將從 6 月 3 日起收到系統更新，以激活內置的 VPN 服務。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;其他設備用戶將無法繼續使用 Google One VPN，這些用戶會被重定向到 Google 支持頁面上的其他 VPN 服務。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143043.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143043.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 03:00:19 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>硅谷興起「愛國主義風潮」</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;華爾街日報説，硅谷投資界正在興起一股 「愛國主義風潮」。&lt;/strong&gt;投資者對美國國防領域的資金投入激增。曾幫助 Facebook、Google 等科技公司起步的投資者們正轉向支持初創企業開發戰場軟件、軍用無人機和自動駕駛潛水艇等領域。這種轉變與中美關係近年來的明顯變化有關。風投人士正適應這種轉變。需要知道的是，硅谷投資者們並非單純因愛國而投資，而是因為這類投資能獲得豐厚回報。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to The Wall Street Journal, there is a growing trend of 「patriotic investing」 in Silicon Valley’s investment community. Investors are significantly increasing their funding in the U.S. defense sector. Investors who previously supported tech companies like Facebook and Google are now shifting towards supporting startups developing battlefield software, military drones, and autonomous submarines. This shift is attributed to the noticeable changes in U.S.-China relations in recent years. Venture capitalists are adapting to this transformation. It is important to note that Silicon Valley investors are not solely driven by patriotism but rather by the potential for substantial returns on these types of investments.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143038.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143038.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 10:40:44 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Edge 瀏覽器修復了兩個安全漏洞</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;微軟於剛剛過去的週末為 Microsoft Edge 124 發佈了安全更新（124.0.2478.97）。&lt;/strong&gt;此次更新修復了兩個安全漏洞，分別是 CVE-2024-30055 和 CVE-2024-30055，前者允許遠程攻擊者通過特製的 HTML 頁面利用堆損壞，後者是 Microsoft Edge 獨有的低嚴重性欺騙漏洞。兩個漏洞均已被野外利用，因此 Edge 用戶應儘快安裝更新。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft has recently released a security update (version 124.0.2478.97) for Microsoft Edge 124 over the past weekend. This update addresses two security vulnerabilities, namely CVE-2024-30055 and CVE-2024-30055. The first vulnerability allows remote attackers to exploit heap corruption using specially crafted HTML pages, while the second vulnerability is a unique low severity deception vulnerability specific to Microsoft Edge. Both vulnerabilities have been exploited in the wild, so it is recommended that Edge users install the update as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143035.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143035.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 09:49:40 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
            <category>瀏覽器</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>衞星互聯網 Starlink 今年有望實現盈利</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SpaceX 旗下的衞星互聯網業務 Starlink（星鏈）有望在 2024 年實現盈利。&lt;/strong&gt;研究機構 Quilty Space 估計，Starlink 在全球擁有近 300 萬客戶，今年的收入將達到 66 億美元，自由現金流估計為 6 億美元，這將是 SpaceX 首次實現盈利。SpaceX 於 2019 年 5 月發射了第一批 60 顆 Starlink V0.9 衞星，截至目前共發射了 6,300 多顆衞星，最後一批衞星將於本週被送入軌道。SpaceX 通過其可重複使用的獵鷹 9 號火箭發射衞星，可大幅降低成本。未來巨型星際飛船火箭投用後，還將允許把大型 Starlink 衞星放置在軌道上，以提供不依賴用戶終端的直接到小區的連接。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;SpaceX’s satellite internet service, Starlink, is expected to become profitable in 2024. Research firm Quilty Space estimates that Starlink has nearly 3 million customers worldwide, with projected revenues of $6.6 billion this year and an estimated free cash flow of $600 million. This would mark the first time SpaceX achieves profitability in its relatively short history. SpaceX launched its first batch of 60 Starlink V0.9 satellites in May 2019 and has since launched over 6,300 satellites. The final batch of satellites is set to be deployed into orbit this week. SpaceX’s reusable Falcon 9 rockets significantly reduce costs for satellite launches. In the future, the deployment of the giant Starship spacecraft will allow for the placement of large Starlink satellites in orbit, providing direct connectivity to communities without relying on user terminals.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143029.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143029.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 09:44:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Edge 瀏覽器將獲得 AI 主題生成器</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;微軟打算為 Edge 瀏覽器推出一個基於 AI 的主題生成器。&lt;/strong&gt;用戶輸入文本提示詞，Edge 即可生成一系列圖像，並可設置為瀏覽器主題，包括圖像的主色調也可作用於瀏覽器框架。該功能計劃 6 月份發佈。組織管理員可使用 「AIGenThemesEnabled」 策略來限制 AI 主題生成功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft plans to introduce an AI-based theme generator for the Edge browser. Users can input text prompts, and Edge will generate a series of images that can be set as browser themes. The main color tones of the images can also be applied to the browser frame. This feature is scheduled for release in June. Organizational administrators can use the 「AIGenThemesEnabled」 policy to restrict the AI theme generation functionality.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143025.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143025.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 13 May 2024 09:31:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>