<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Mon, 17 Jun 2024 10:40:33 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>Android 項目主要領導者 Dave Burke 在谷歌內部調崗</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;谷歌工程副總裁戴夫·伯克（Dave Burke）將在 Google 內部調崗。&lt;/strong&gt;作為 Android 項目的主要領導者之一，Dave Burke 以在 I/O 開發者大會上的 Google 主題演講而聞名，他在演講中討論新的 Android 功能。調崗後，他將轉向 AI 和生物技術領域。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Dave Burke 的調崗是 Google 內部重組的一部分——Google 正在將其 Android 和 ChromeOS 等操作系統開發部門與 Pixel 手機和 Chromebook 等硬件開發部門合併。該公司將把 Android 內核和框架插入 ChromeOS。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google engineering VP Dave Burke is shifting roles within Google. One of the lead executives for the Android project, Burke was known for leading Google’s keynote at the I/O developer conference, where he’d discuss new Android features. In his new role, he’ll be moving to work on AI and biotech. Burke’s shift is part of a reorganization within Google that will see the company combine its operating system development efforts across Android and ChromeOS with its hardware development for devices like Pixel phones and Chromebooks. The company will merge the core of Android with ChromeOS.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143464.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143464.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 10:11:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Drive 新功能：郵件提醒查看他人分享的文件</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/2024061309350985.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;Google 雲端硬盤已開始發送電子郵件，以提醒客戶處理與他們共享但尚未查看的文件。&lt;/strong&gt;谷歌稱其為 Drive Digest，只有當客戶在 7 天內未登錄並且其他用戶共享了他們尚未查看的文件時，他們才會收到電子郵件提醒。這是一項 Workspace 功能，尚不清楚是否適用於私人帳戶。該功能將在未來幾周內發佈，谷歌允許在設置中關閉通知。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Drive is starting to send out emails to remind customers about files shared with them that they haven’t gotten around to looking at yet. Google calls it Drive Digest , and you’ll only get the email reminders if you haven’t signed in for seven days and you have files shared with you that you haven’t viewed. This is a Workspace feature, and it’s not clear if it will also be available to personal accounts. The rollout of this feature will happen over the next few weeks, and Google will let you turn off the notifications in your settings .&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143458.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143458.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 09:36:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>你在 X（Twitter）的點贊現在是私密的</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-image&quot;&gt;
&lt;figure class=&quot;aligncenter size-full is-resized&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/wp-content/uploads/2024/06/2024061309240816.png&quot; referrerpolicy=&quot;no-referrer&quot;&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;X 已經開始隱藏用戶的 「喜歡」/點贊數據——貼子仍會顯示收到了多少贊，但在某位用戶的主頁無法再看到 TA 點讚的內容。&lt;/strong&gt;貼子作者仍能繼續看到誰點讚了自己的帖子。我們實測看到，這項改動已經生效，X 已經彈窗進行提示 「你的點贊現在是私密的」。X（Twitter）表示，個人點贊數據公開經常受到批評，因為用戶有時會將該機制用作書籤，而不代表他們喜歡或支持某篇帖子。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;由於隱私增強，上述改動可能會進一步提升 X（Twitter）用戶點讚的積極性。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;X has begun hiding users’ like/favorite counts — posts will still show how many likes they have received, but there’s no longer any way to see what someone has liked from their profile. The author of a post will still be able to see who liked their post. The change appears to be rolling out now, with X showing a pop-up notification that reads, 「Your likes are now private.」 X (Twitter) said that public like counts were often criticized because people sometimes used the feature as a bookmarking tool rather than a way to indicate that they enjoyed or supported a tweet.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143447.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143447.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 09:31:05 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>2024 年 6 月更新修復了 Win11 任務欄卡頓/無響應問題</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，微軟表示，&lt;strong&gt;本週二發佈的 2024 年 6 月的 Patch Tuesday 更新，已修復了 Windows 11 任務欄偶爾出現卡頓、無響應、消失後重顯等問題，以及 Windows 11 21H2 中的 BitLocker 65000 錯誤。&lt;/strong&gt;BitLocker 65000 錯誤出現於去年 10 月。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;微軟本週二發佈了 2024 年 6 月的 Patch Tuesday 更新，適用於 Windows 11（KB5039212 / KB5039213）和 Windows 10（KB5039211 / KB5039217 / KB5039214 / KB5039225）。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft says that this week’s Patch Tuesday updates, released on June 13, 2023, fixes issues with the Windows 11 taskbar occasionally getting stuck or unresponsive, disappearing and reappearing, and the BitLocker 65000 error that started appearing in Windows 11 21H2 in October last year.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Microsoft released the June 2023 Patch Tuesday updates on Tuesday and they include updates for Windows 11 (KB5039212 / KB5039213) and Windows 10 (KB5039211 / KB5039217 / KB5039214 / KB5039225).&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143435.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143435.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 03:34:46 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>Windows 11</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Spotify 高保真訂閲每月額外收費 5 美元</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;據彭博社，音頻流媒體平台 Spotify 的高保真音頻訂閲計劃每月額外收費 5 美元。&lt;/strong&gt;這項訂閲計劃可能在今年晚些時候發佈。除了更高質量的音頻外，高保真計劃訂戶將獲得更多個性化播放列表，此外客戶可以創建帶有提示的播放列表，然後 Spotify 會嘗試找到正確的歌曲。Spotify 尚未迴應上述傳聞。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;According to Bloomberg, audio streaming platform Spotify is planning to introduce a high-fidelity audio subscription plan with an additional monthly charge of $5. This subscription plan is expected to be released later this year. In addition to higher quality audio, high-fidelity plan subscribers will have access to more personalized playlists. Furthermore, customers will be able to create playlists with cues, and Spotify will attempt to find the right songs. Spotify has not yet responded to the aforementioned rumors.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143402.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143402.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Thu, 13 Jun 2024 02:33:42 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>