<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Jun 2024 16:35:14 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>截屏工具 FastStone Capture 支持「固定到屏幕」和「文本提取」</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;備受歡迎的 Windows 截屏工具 FastStone Capture 於 2024 年 5 月底發佈了最新版本，即 FastStone Capture 10.5（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faststone.org/FSCaptureDownload.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;官網下載頁&lt;/a&gt;）。&lt;/strong&gt;新版本新增了 「固定到屏幕」 和 「捕獲文本」 功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;顧名思義，「固定到屏幕」（界面上譯為 「屏幕貼圖」）允許用戶將截屏固定在電腦屏幕上，以便在不同的應用程序之間切換。「捕獲文本」 則允許用戶直接從屏幕截圖中提取文本。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;添加了 「固定到屏幕」。此功能允許您在其他窗口（如便箋）上固定和註釋屏幕截圖。優勢包括：
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;參考便利性：如果您正在處理一項需要您經常參考屏幕截圖的任務，將其固定在屏幕上可以使您免於不斷切換窗口或應用程序。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;高效比較：當您需要比較應用程序之間的數據時，固定屏幕截圖可以更輕鬆地同時查看兩組數據，而無需第二台顯示器。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;視覺提醒：固定捕獲可以作為需要完成的任務或需要注意的信息的視覺提醒，從而減少忘記重要細節的機會。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;添加了 「捕獲文本」。此功能可以提取文本並使其可立即編輯，從而節省時間和精力，而不是從屏幕截圖中手動鍵入文本。它需要 Windows 10/11。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;進行了其他改進和錯誤修復&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The popular Windows screenshot tool, FastStone Capture, released its latest version, FastStone Capture 10.5, at the end of May 2024. The new version introduces the 「Pin to Screen」 and 「Capture Text」 features.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, the 「Pin to Screen」 (translated as 「Screen Magnifier」 in the interface) allows users to pin the screenshot to their computer screen for easy switching between different applications. The 「Capture Text」 feature enables users to extract text directly from the screen captures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Screen Recorder&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplified&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Start Recording&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;window. Switch between simplified mode and detailed mode with just a single click&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enable&lt;/strong&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;disable&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;devices&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;like Microphone, Speaker, and Webcam directly&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;within&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Start Recording&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Enhanced&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Eraser&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Draw tool:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show a&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;circular cursor&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;to indicate the area to be erased.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Right click mouse to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;pick a screen color&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Scroll mouse wheel to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;adjust eraser size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Save dialog&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Scan&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;tool with improved functionality and user interface.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Added 「&lt;strong&gt;Save All (same name)&lt;/strong&gt;」 option (Ctrl+Alt+S) to the File menu in FastStone Editor, allowing you to save multiple images with the same name and a sequential number&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Many other small enhancements and bug fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143235.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143235.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 16:31:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>圖形圖像</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>電子書網站 Z-Library 主要域名再被查封</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;電子書網站 Z-Library 稱其一個主要域名被當局查封，該網站因此遭遇技術問題，目前仍在努力恢復。&lt;/strong&gt;該網站沒有提及查封域名的當局名稱。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;親愛的 Z-Librarians，&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;由於我們的一個主要域名被沒收，我們正在經歷一些技術問題。我們的團隊正在努力恢復功能。&lt;br&gt;捐款的入賬可能會有延遲，但請不要擔心 – 系統將自動將其計入，並儘快升級您的賬戶為高級會員狀態。&lt;br&gt;請注意，可能會有人冒充我們的圖書館進行欺詐活動，同時請記住，我們的網站不提供終身高級會員資格。該網站仍然可以通過以下鏈接訪問：&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;singlelogin.re&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;singlelogin.rs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;我們目前正在努力恢復我們的支持團隊，以便他們能夠回覆您的所有消息。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The e-book website Z-Library has reported that one of its main domains has been seized by authorities, resulting in technical issues for the website. Efforts are currently underway to restore its functionality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Dear Z-Librarians,&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Since one of our main domains was seized, we are experiencing some technical issues. Our team is already working to restore functionality.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;There may be delays in crediting donations, but don’t worry – the system will automatically credit them and upgrade your accounts to premium status as soon as possible.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Please pay attention to possible fraudulent activities on behalf of our library, and remember that our site does not offer lifetime premium status. The website is still available via the links below:&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;singlelogin.re&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;singlelogin.rs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;We are currently working on getting our support team back up, so they can reply to all your messages.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Thank you for your understanding and patience ❤️&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143223.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143223.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:55:18 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[技巧] 關閉 Firefox 安卓版的遙測功能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;要關閉 Firefox 安卓版的遙測功能非常簡單，只需進入瀏覽器的設置界面，點擊數據收集，將以下三項開關關即可。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;使用率和技術數據&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;營銷數據&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;研究&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;



&lt;p&gt;關閉 Firefox 安卓版的遙測功能可&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/143209.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;提升瀏覽器的性能&lt;/a&gt;。&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143216.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143216.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:43:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>遙測功能降低了 Firefox 安卓版的性能</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;遙測功能似乎影響了 &lt;strong&gt;Firefox 安卓版&lt;/strong&gt;的性能，Mozilla 已對此展開調查。&lt;/strong&gt;根據初步報告，遙測會增加額外的 CPU 時間。其中一項測試顯示，在加載 CNN 網站時，遙測使 Firefox 安卓版增加了額外的 16.5 秒 CPU 時間。此外，瀏覽器的啓動也受到遙測的影響——與關閉遙測相比，啓動瀏覽器會增加 40% 的 CPU 時間。Mozilla 表示，問題的根源在於 Android 上的遙測更新沒有進行分組，因此每次更新都會單獨添加到數據庫中。此外，每次更新都會將整個數據庫寫入磁盤。由於遙測數據被廣泛收集，因此會執行大量的寫操作。這會對瀏覽器的啓動、網頁加載和媒體播放等方面產生影響。&lt;strong&gt;在 Mozilla 改進之前，Android 用戶可以選擇在瀏覽器中關閉遙測以獲得更好的性能。&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.ruancan.com/p/143216.html&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;關閉方法&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The telemetry feature of Firefox for Android appears to be impacting the performance of the browser, and Mozilla has initiated an investigation into this matter. According to preliminary reports, telemetry adds additional CPU time. One test showed that while loading the CNN website, telemetry added an extra 16.5 seconds of CPU time to Firefox for Android. Additionally, the startup of the browser is also affected by telemetry, with a 40% increase in CPU time compared to when telemetry is disabled. Mozilla states that the root cause of the issue lies in the fact that telemetry updates on Android are not grouped, leading to individual additions to the database with each update. Furthermore, every update requires writing the entire database to disk. Since telemetry data is collected extensively, it results in a significant number of write operations. This has an impact on browser startup, webpage loading, and media playback. Until Mozilla addresses the issue, Android users can choose to disable telemetry in the browser for improved performance.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143209.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143209.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:43:07 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>安卓應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Netflix 宣佈將推出《我的世界》動畫劇集</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Netflix 宣佈將推出一部圍繞視頻遊戲 Minecraft（我的世界）的動畫劇集。&lt;/strong&gt;這家流媒體平台提到了一個 「帶有全新角色的原創故事」。發佈日期尚未公佈。已釋出的預告片展示了下界與爬行者的地下世界。這部劇集由加拿大工作室 WildBrain Studios 製作，該機構曾為 Netflix 製作過幾部兒童劇集和《Sonic Prime》。此外，還有一部 Minecraft 主題電影正在開發中，傑克·布萊克（Jack Black）可能會扮演主角。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Netflix has announced the upcoming release of an animated series based on the video game Minecraft. The streaming platform mentions an 「original story with new characters.」 The release date has not been revealed yet. The teaser trailer showcases the Nether, an underground world, and a Creeper. There is no indication of the plot at this time. The animated series is being produced by Canadian studio WildBrain Studios, known for creating several children’s series and 「Sonic Prime」 for Netflix. Additionally, there is an ongoing development of a Minecraft-themed film, with actor Jack Black rumored to have a leading role.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143204.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143204.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Fri, 31 May 2024 10:22:08 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>影音娛樂</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>