<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss
    xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0">
    <channel>
        <title>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊</title>
        <link>https://www.ruancan.com</link>
        <atom:link href="http://rsshub.app/ruancan" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"></atom:link>
        <description>軟餐 - 新鮮軟件資訊 - Made with love by RSSHub(https://github.com/DIYgod/RSSHub)</description>
        <generator>RSSHub</generator>
        <webMaster>i@diygod.me (DIYgod)</webMaster>
        <language>en</language>
        <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Jun 2024 16:43:37 GMT</lastBuildDate>
        <ttl>180</ttl>
        <item>
            <title>X（Twitter）對成人內容放寬政策</title>
            <description>&lt;div class=&quot;wp-block-wpcom-alert&quot;&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert alert-info block-alert&quot; role=&quot;alert&quot;&gt;&lt;i class=&quot;wpcom-icon fa fa-info-circle icon-el&quot;&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;div class=&quot;alert-content&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;本文是客觀報道，本站及作者對報道對象不持立場。&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;/div&gt;



&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;X（Twitter）似乎決定針對成人內容放寬政策。&lt;/strong&gt;因為該平台最近發佈了一個新的成人內容政策頁面。頁面顯示，X 用戶現在可以發佈帶有 「成人裸體或性行為」 的內容，但將有一些限制。該平台認為此類內容 「可以成為一種合法的藝術表達形式」。與此同時，X 將針對這些內容覆蓋內容警告信息，未登記生日的未成年用戶將無法通過內容警告以瀏覽這些內容。X 賬戶頭像或橫幅中也禁止放置成人內容。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;這並不意味着 X 允許任何成人內容，因為該平台仍然禁止任何可以標記為 「剝削、未經同意、物化、性化或傷害未成年人以及淫穢行為」 的成人內容。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;這次同時發佈的還有一個新的暴力內容政策頁面。X 官方表示，這兩個新政策頁面都取代了其以前的敏感媒體和暴力言論政策。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;X (Twitter) appears to have decided to relax its policies against adult content. The platform recently published a new adult content policy page , which reveals that X users are now able to post content that features 「nudity or sexual activity」 so long as certain restrictions are met. The platform believes that such content 「can be a legitimate form of artistic expression.」 X will, however, cover such content with an interstitial warning, and underage users who have not registered their birthday will not be able to proceed past the warning to view the content. Adult content will also be prohibited in X account profile pictures and banners. This doesn’t mean that X will allow any adult content, as the platform will still ban any adult content that could be flagged as 「exploitative, non-consensual, objectifying, dehumanizing or grooming minors, as well as pornography.」 Also rolling out today is a new support page for its violent content policy . 「These new policy pages replace our previous Sensitive Media and Violent Speech policies,」 an X spokesperson says.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143270.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143270.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Tue, 04 Jun 2024 11:32:11 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>[清單] 2024 年 5 月 Telegram 更新要點</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，Telegram（電報）於上個月底發佈了 2024 年 5 月份的版本更新。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;我們從冗長的更新日誌中梳理了更新要點。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://telegram.org/blog/message-effects-and-more#message-effects&quot;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;私聊消息動畫效果&lt;/strong&gt;。現在，Telegram 私聊消息可以動畫效果發送，對方打開聊天時會播放這些效果。Telegram 免費提供 6 種效果，Telegram Premium 用戶可解鎖數百種效果。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;媒體上方的字幕。&lt;/strong&gt;標題現在可移動到媒體上方。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;手機號碼的快速操作&lt;/strong&gt;。在聊天中點擊手機號碼會打開新菜單，可快速發送消息、通話或將號碼添加為聯繫人。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;主題標籤搜索&lt;/strong&gt;。現在，在任何聊天中點擊主題標籤可顯示來自公共頻道的搜索結果。例如快速找到頻 &lt;code&gt;#news&lt;/code&gt;&amp;nbsp; 或 &lt;code&gt;#travel&lt;/code&gt;&amp;nbsp; 視頻。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;可摺疊的引用&lt;/strong&gt;。現在可將文本片段隱藏在摺疊的引用塊中，消息更緊湊。只需添加引用格式，並在輸入框中點擊摺疊按鈕。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;macOS 上的彩色通話&lt;/strong&gt;。現在，Telegram 原生 macOS 應用程序用戶可使用彩色通話界面，包括動態背景和時尚動畫。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143243.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143243.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 15:00:25 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>特朗普入駐 TikTok</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;共和黨總統候選人特朗普 (Donald Trump) 入駐了短視頻平台 TikTok。&lt;/strong&gt;該賬號在週日早間粉絲超過 80 萬。上週六晚，特朗普發佈一段了 13 秒的短視頻，是他在新澤西州紐瓦克的終極格鬥冠軍賽（簡稱 UFC) 活動的視頻。視頻中，特朗普在賽場內向粉絲致意。特朗普希望通過加入 TikTok 來拉攏年輕選民。而就在四年前，特朗普在總統任上曾試圖下令封禁 TikTok，但因法律問題未能如願。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Republican presidential candidate Donald Trump has joined the short video platform TikTok. The account garnered over 800,000 followers on Sunday morning. Last Saturday night, Trump released a 13-second video showcasing his presence at the Ultimate Fighting Championship (UFC) event in Newark, New Jersey. In the video, Trump greeted his fans inside the arena. By joining TikTok, Trump aims to attract young voters. Interestingly, just four years ago, during his presidency, Trump attempted to ban TikTok, but his efforts were hindered by legal challenges.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143241.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143241.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:54:13 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>業界</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>Google Cloud 推出條件寬鬆的 90 天試用計劃</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，谷歌雲（Google Cloud）為了推廣 Vertex AI，日前推出了免費試用計劃，用戶可從 Google Cloud 獲得 150 美元的贈送金，可在 3 個月內體驗 Vertex AI 及 Google Cloud，包括在 Google Cloud 上創建虛擬機。&lt;strong&gt;我們測試發現，申請這項體驗計劃無需驗證信用卡或銀行卡，甚至點擊 「免費試用 Vertex AI」 體驗按鈕，即可直接通過申請。&lt;/strong&gt;後續還可激活賬號（需驗卡）可再獲得 150 美元贈金。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;如果讀者在申請時彈出驗證信用卡或銀行卡界面，説明 IP 不滿足條件，可考慮更換一個新的 IP 再次申請。&lt;br&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai?hl=zh_cn&quot;&gt;https://cloud.google.com/vertex-ai?hl=zh_cn&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;Google Cloud has recently launched a free trial program to promote Vertex AI. Users can receive a $150 credit from Google Cloud to experience Vertex AI and Google Cloud services for three months, including creating virtual machines on Google Cloud. Our testing has found that applying for this trial program does not require credit card or bank card verification. Users can simply click the 「Free Trial Vertex AI」 button to apply directly. Afterward, activating the account (requires card verification) will provide an additional $150 credit.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;If readers encounter a credit card or bank card verification prompt during the application process, it indicates that the IP does not meet the requirements. In this case, consider changing to a new IP and reapplying.&lt;/p&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143238.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143238.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Mon, 03 Jun 2024 03:12:24 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>網絡應用</category>
        </item>
        <item>
            <title>截屏工具 FastStone Capture 支持「固定到屏幕」和「文本提取」</title>
            <description>&lt;p&gt;軟餐獲悉，&lt;strong&gt;備受歡迎的 Windows 截屏工具 FastStone Capture 於 2024 年 5 月底發佈了最新版本，即 FastStone Capture 10.5（&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.faststone.org/FSCaptureDownload.htm&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; rel=&quot;noreferrer noopener nofollow&quot;&gt;官網下載頁&lt;/a&gt;）。&lt;/strong&gt;新版本新增了 「固定到屏幕」 和 「捕獲文本」 功能。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;顧名思義，「固定到屏幕」（界面上譯為 「屏幕貼圖」）允許用戶將截屏固定在電腦屏幕上，以便在不同的應用程序之間切換。「捕獲文本」 則允許用戶直接從屏幕截圖中提取文本。&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;添加了 「固定到屏幕」。此功能允許您在其他窗口（如便箋）上固定和註釋屏幕截圖。優勢包括：
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;參考便利性：如果您正在處理一項需要您經常參考屏幕截圖的任務，將其固定在屏幕上可以使您免於不斷切換窗口或應用程序。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;高效比較：當您需要比較應用程序之間的數據時，固定屏幕截圖可以更輕鬆地同時查看兩組數據，而無需第二台顯示器。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;視覺提醒：固定捕獲可以作為需要完成的任務或需要注意的信息的視覺提醒，從而減少忘記重要細節的機會。&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;添加了 「捕獲文本」。此功能可以提取文本並使其可立即編輯，從而節省時間和精力，而不是從屏幕截圖中手動鍵入文本。它需要 Windows 10/11。&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;進行了其他改進和錯誤修復&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;



&lt;hr class=&quot;wp-block-separator has-alpha-channel-opacity&quot;&gt;



&lt;p&gt;The popular Windows screenshot tool, FastStone Capture, released its latest version, FastStone Capture 10.5, at the end of May 2024. The new version introduces the 「Pin to Screen」 and 「Capture Text」 features.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;p&gt;As the name suggests, the 「Pin to Screen」 (translated as 「Screen Magnifier」 in the interface) allows users to pin the screenshot to their computer screen for easy switching between different applications. The 「Capture Text」 feature enables users to extract text directly from the screen captures.&lt;/p&gt;



&lt;blockquote class=&quot;wp-block-quote is-layout-flow wp-block-quote-is-layout-flow&quot;&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Enhanced&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Screen Recorder&lt;/strong&gt;:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Simplified&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Start Recording&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;window. Switch between simplified mode and detailed mode with just a single click&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Enable&lt;/strong&gt;/&lt;strong&gt;disable&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;devices&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;like Microphone, Speaker, and Webcam directly&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;within&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Start Recording&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;window&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Enhanced&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Eraser&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in Draw tool:
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Show a&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;circular cursor&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;to indicate the area to be erased.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Right click mouse to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;pick a screen color&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Scroll mouse wheel to&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;adjust eraser size&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Enhanced the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Save dialog&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;in the&amp;nbsp;&lt;strong&gt;Scan&lt;/strong&gt;&amp;nbsp;tool with improved functionality and user interface.&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Added 「&lt;strong&gt;Save All (same name)&lt;/strong&gt;」 option (Ctrl+Alt+S) to the File menu in FastStone Editor, allowing you to save multiple images with the same name and a sequential number&lt;/li&gt;



&lt;li&gt;Many other small enhancements and bug fixes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
                                                                                </description>
            <link>https://www.ruancan.com/p/143235.html</link>
            <guid isPermaLink="false">https://www.ruancan.com/p/143235.html</guid>
            <pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2024 16:31:41 GMT</pubDate>
            <category>圖形圖像</category>
        </item>
    </channel>
</rss>